<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CARB on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/tags/carb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CARB on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/tags/carb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Price of carbon increases slightly at CARB&#39;s May auction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-05-30-price-of-carbon-increases-slightly-at-carb-s-may-auction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-05-30-price-of-carbon-increases-slightly-at-carb-s-may-auction/</guid>
      <description>The price of carbon per metric tonne rose at the May auction hosted by the California Air Resources Board (CARB). According to CARB’s recent Auction Information and Results from their auction on May 17, the settlement price of one metric tonne of carbon dioxide equivalent was $30.33, an increase from prices of $27.85 posted in CARB’s last auction in February 2023.&#xA;Here is the trend in auction settlement prices from CARB since 2018:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A look at the price of carbon from February&#39;s CARB auction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-03-02-a-look-at-the-price-of-carbon-from-february-s-carb-auction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-03-02-a-look-at-the-price-of-carbon-from-february-s-carb-auction/</guid>
      <description>The price of carbon per metric tonne rose by about a dollar at the February auction hosted by the California Air Resources Board (CARB). According to CARB’s recent Auction Information and Results from their auction on February 15, the settlement price of one metric tonne of carbon was $27.85, an increase from prices of $26.80 posted in CARB’s last auction in November 2022.&#xA;Here is the trend in auction settlement prices from CARB since 2018:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Price of carbon remains steady since last quarter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-12-21-price-of-carbon-remains-steady-since-last-quarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-12-21-price-of-carbon-remains-steady-since-last-quarter/</guid>
      <description>The price of carbon per metric tonne decreased slightly at a recent auction hosted by the California Air Resources Board (CARB). According to CARB’s recent Auction Information and Results from their auction on November 16, the settlement price of one metric tonne of carbon was $26.80, a slight decrease from prices of $27.00 posted in CARB’s last auction in August 2022.&#xA;Here is the trend in auction settlement prices from CARB since 2018:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent research insights in forest biomass and carbon estimation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/events/2022-12-01-recent-research-insights-in-forest-biomass-and-carbon-estimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/events/2022-12-01-recent-research-insights-in-forest-biomass-and-carbon-estimation/</guid>
      <description>Recent research within the forest biometrics community is helping to generate more precise estimates of forest carbon using new methods and technologies. This presentation was delivered to the California Air Resources Board Public Workshop on US Forest Projects Compliance Offset Protocol on November 30, 2022.&#xA;READ THE SLIDES.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Price of carbon in CARB decreases slightly</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-09-07-price-of-carbon-in-carb-decreases-slightly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-09-07-price-of-carbon-in-carb-decreases-slightly/</guid>
      <description>The price of carbon per metric tonne decreased slightly at a recent auction hosted by the California Air Resources Board (CARB). According to CARB’s recent Auction Information and Results from their auction on August 17, the settlement price of one metric tonne of carbon was $27.00. This represents a 12% decrease from prices of $30.85 posted in CARB’s last auction in May 2022.&#xA;I’ve been keeping track of the price of carbon at CARB auctions for some time.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
