<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Viz on Arbor Custom Analytics</title>
    <link>/tags/data-viz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Viz on Arbor Custom Analytics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/data-viz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Google Forms to analyze confidence intervals: a teaching statistics activity</title>
      <link>/post/using-google-forms-to-analyze-confidence-intervals-a-teaching-statistics-activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/using-google-forms-to-analyze-confidence-intervals-a-teaching-statistics-activity/</guid>
      <description>This post describes how the concepts of confidence intervals can be taught to students. The ideal participants are undergraduate students in an introductory statistics. The in-class activity reveals to students that most people are overconfident in their estimation of uncertainty. The activity uses the example of moose, a charismatic wildlife species in Minnesota.
IntroductionDemonstrations of data and statistical concepts are effective when they are designed with a structure that encourages participation in the classroom 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making animated GIFs in R: ten years of emerald ash borer spread in Minnesota </title>
      <link>/post/making-animated-gif-maps-in-r-visualizing-ten-years-of-emerald-ash-borer-spread-in-minnesota/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/making-animated-gif-maps-in-r-visualizing-ten-years-of-emerald-ash-borer-spread-in-minnesota/</guid>
      <description>The popularity of GIFs have exploded in recent years and they give photojournalists a great way to tell a story. Sometimes the right GIF image can bring data to life.
The general process to make a GIF image with maps in R is:
1. Create the images you want (e.g., using ggplot),
2. Stitch the images together with magick, and
3. Write the images as a GIF and share!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presenting regression results better with forest plots</title>
      <link>/post/presenting-regression-results-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/presenting-regression-results-better/</guid>
      <description>I was inspired by Sara Richter’s presentation at the 2019 Conference on Statistical Practice titled “Easy Ways to Make Data Visualizations More Effective”. One of the themes I took away from Sara’s presentation was that data visualization needs to be practiced, but good data visualization doesn’t need to be difficult to be done well.
When presenting results from a regression, people often use tables. While this is good if we need the true value of something, tables may not be good if we seek to convey general trends in our results.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>