<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Classification on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/tags/classification/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Classification on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/tags/classification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Random forests in a nutshell</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/random-forests-in-a-nutshell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/random-forests-in-a-nutshell/</guid>
      <description>Random forests have exploded in popularity in the forestry discipline in recent years. Random forests (RF) are a quantitative tool categorized as a machine learning technique. Analysts prefer to use RF methods because they can handle large amounts of data, provide the relative importance of a many variables, and can be applied to classification or regression problems.&#xA;The following graph shows the number of articles from four common journals in the forestry discipline that contained the term “random forests” in the article.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to determine accuracy of classification models (with forestry data)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/how-to-determine-accuracy-of-classification-models-with-forestry-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/how-to-determine-accuracy-of-classification-models-with-forestry-data/</guid>
      <description>Classification is the process when you predict something, and that something is a class or label. It’s widely used when analyzing and modeling forestry data. Data scientists use if often as one of the many machine learning algorithms.&#xA;You might have learned about classification in the context of logistic regression. In logistic regression, your outcome is a binary class of data. For example, a tree can be alive or dead.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
