<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guest Workers on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/tags/guest-workers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guest Workers on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/tags/guest-workers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>H-2B guest workers in forestry: a review of 2022 data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-06-15-h-2b-guest-workers-in-forestry-a-review-of-2022-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-06-15-h-2b-guest-workers-in-forestry-a-review-of-2022-data/</guid>
      <description>Guest workers regenerating a northern Minnesota forest. (photo: @Chris_KTDunham, Twitter)&#xD;Guest workers hired through the H-2B visa program get jobs done. This is especially true across many forestry companies. Guest workers plant trees, clear brush, conduct vegetation management, and assist in tree nursery production.&#xA;A strong guest worker program can lead to a future forest products industry that is healthy and sustainable in the long term. The H-2B program organized through the US Department of Labor provides opportunities to hire temporary foreign workers to fill low-skill and non-agricultural positions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>H-2B workers: essential to the forest products industry</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-11-13-h-2b-workers-essential-to-the-forest-products-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-11-13-h-2b-workers-essential-to-the-forest-products-industry/</guid>
      <description>In Cabinet Battle #1, one of the most popular songs from the musical Hamilton, Alexander Hamilton and Thomas Jefferson discuss the role of the federal government in assuming the financial debt of states. It’s the late 1780s, and Hamilton has ideas for a national bank that Jefferson and many Southerners aren’t fans of.&#xA;Near the end of Hamilton’s verse, he states that it’s odd to take “civics lessons from a slaver”.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>H-2B guest workers in forestry: by the numbers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/h-2b-forestry-and-conservation-workers-by-the-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/h-2b-forestry-and-conservation-workers-by-the-numbers/</guid>
      <description>Guest workers regenerating a northern Minnesota forest. (photo: @Chris_KTDunham, Twitter)&#xA;Guest workers hired through the H-2B visa program get jobs done. This is especially true across many forestry companies. Guest workers plant trees, conduct silvicultural treatments, and assist in tree nursery production.&#xA;A strong guest worker program can lead to a future forest products industry that is healthy and sustainable in the long term.&#xA;Last week, the Trump administration announced 35,000 additional seasonal H-2B guest worker visas available in 2020.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
