<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>forest carbon on </title>
    <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/tags/forest-carbon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in forest carbon on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arbor-analytics.com/tags/forest-carbon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Forest carbon in Maine: an introduction</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2022-03-10-forest-carbon-in-maine-an-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2022-03-10-forest-carbon-in-maine-an-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Note: This post is based on an article Matt wrote for the Great Lakes Timber Professionals Association’s magazine in January 2022. Interested in an article like this for your state? Email Matt with any requests.
One of the many benefits that trees provide is removing carbon dioxide from the air. Carbon dioxide is the leading source of greenhouse gas emissions in the United States.
In trees and forests, carbon is measured by how much is stored and sequestered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does the price of carbon have to be for landowners to enroll in carbon markets?</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2022-02-22-what-does-the-price-of-carbon-have-to-be-for-landowners-to-enroll-in-carbon-markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2022-02-22-what-does-the-price-of-carbon-have-to-be-for-landowners-to-enroll-in-carbon-markets/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionCarbon has quickly become one of the most talked about commodities in our forests today. A variety of new and emerging carbon market programs are paying landowners for the carbon in their forests Carbon is the currency of interest when discussing trees and forests as natural climate solutions.
While compliance-driven markets such as the California Air Resource Board’s (CARB) Cap-and-Trade Regulation and their associated Forest Offset Protocol have existed for several years, it has primarily targeted large landowners with thousands of acres.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forest carbon Emerging opportunities in Lake States Forests</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/events/2021-12-10-forest-carbon-emerging-opportunities-in-lake-states-forests/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/events/2021-12-10-forest-carbon-emerging-opportunities-in-lake-states-forests/</guid>
      <description>Forest carbon presents many opportunities for forest resources professionals. This presentation was a part of a panel at the Forest Resources Association’s Lake States Winter Meeting on forest carbon.
READ THE SLIDES.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Price of carbon recently hit a record high</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-12-10-price-of-carbon-recently-hit-a-record-high/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-12-10-price-of-carbon-recently-hit-a-record-high/</guid>
      <description>The price of carbon per metric tonne reached a record high at a recent auction hosted by the California Air Resources Board (CARB). According to CARB’s recent Auction Information and Results from November 2021, the settlement price of one metric tonne of carbon was $28.26. This represents a 21% increase from prices of $23.30 as recent as August 2021.
Auction reserve prices have increased marginally over the last several years, ranging from $14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CO2 offsets and trips to the family cabin</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-11-27-co2-offsets-and-trips-to-the-family-cabin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-11-27-co2-offsets-and-trips-to-the-family-cabin/</guid>
      <description>Often I think that if the numbers behind forest carbon estimates were easier to calculate and interpret, we’d all have a better understanding of the carbon stored and sequestered in our forests. It starts simple when we say that “half of the biomass of a tree is carbon”. But beyond that, transitions between gases and solids and conversions between metric and English units quickly add complexity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing forest carbon trends in the last thirty years</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-11-15-visualizing-forest-carbon-tredns-in-the-last-30-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-11-15-visualizing-forest-carbon-tredns-in-the-last-30-years/</guid>
      <description>Trees and forests sequester carbon dioxide and other greenhouse gases from the atmosphere. This makes them a natural climate solution. This also encourages managers to quantify carbon attributes along with the myriad of other benefits that forests provide.
The value of carbon in forests has seen a tremendous increase in recent years. The increased role of forests in meeting climate challenges has required analysts to have a better understanding of carbon attributes in the forests they work in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If 50% of a tree&#39;s biomass is carbon, what&#39;s the other half?</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-08-22-if-50-of-a-tree-s-biomass-is-carbon-what-s-the-other-half/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-08-22-if-50-of-a-tree-s-biomass-is-carbon-what-s-the-other-half/</guid>
      <description>“You wrote earlier that “since half of biomass is carbon, I multiply by 0.5.” What is the other half of biomass?&#34;
I was sent this question this question over email last week. As foresters, we’re often concerned with only carbon stored and sequestered in trees. But the are other elements that form the chemical composition of wood. While there are slight deviations to the “50% of biomass in wood is carbon” assumption, it is a statement that provides an approximation about the amount of carbon in wood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New eBook: Forest Carbon by the Numbers</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-08-12-new-ebook-forest-carbon-by-the-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-08-12-new-ebook-forest-carbon-by-the-numbers/</guid>
      <description>Now available on Amazon is Forest Carbon by the Numbers: Understanding the Hottest Forest Product of the 2020s.
Carbon is becoming a highly valued commodity of forests. Trees sequester carbon dioxide and turn it into wood, storing carbon in forests and long-lived forest products for long time periods. Despite the increased recognition of carbon as a natural climate solution and several emerging markets that monetize it, few professionals in forestry and natural resources have a grasp on the amount and extent of forest carbon in the ecosystems they work in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forest carbon: key definitions and numbers in perspective  </title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-08-08-forest-carbon-key-definitions-and-numbers-in-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-08-08-forest-carbon-key-definitions-and-numbers-in-perspective/</guid>
      <description>Carbon storage in US forests. Source: USDA Forest Service.
Carbon is quickly becoming one of the hottest forest products of the 2020s. The term “carbon” is a broad one, and when reading an article or listening to a speaker, you may not know exactly which process or specific term is being referred to.
Here are a few basic terms that will help guide your understanding:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harvested wood products: a growing contributor to US carbon storage</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-05-15-harvested-wood-products-an-increasing-contributor-to-us-carbon-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-05-15-harvested-wood-products-an-increasing-contributor-to-us-carbon-storage/</guid>
      <description>There has been a lot of talk recently about the importance of carbon in forests. Carbon dioxide is the leading source of greenhouse gas emissions, resulting from burning fossil fuels for transportation and energy and producing electricity, among other sources. Trees sequester carbon dioxide from the air and turn it into carbon stored in wood. As a result, healthy trees and forests increase carbon storage and avoid greenhouse gas emissions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five forest carbon markets for small landowners</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-03-20-an-overview-of-forest-carbon-markets-for-small-landowners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-03-20-an-overview-of-forest-carbon-markets-for-small-landowners/</guid>
      <description>Voluntary forest carbon markets have expanded considerably over the last year. While compliance markets such as the California Air Resource Board’s Cap-and-Trade Regulation and their associated Forest Offset Protocol have existed for several years, it has primarily targeted large landowners with thousands of acres.
One of the benefits of newer voluntary forest carbon programs is that they typically have small minimum acreage requirements and shorter contract lengths.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
