<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Forest Products on Arbor Analytics</title>
    <link>/tags/forest-products/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Forest Products on Arbor Analytics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/forest-products/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How many trees make a mass timber building?</title>
      <link>/post/how-many-trees-make-a-mass-timber-building/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-many-trees-make-a-mass-timber-building/</guid>
      <description>The T3 in Minneapolis, Minnesota is a mass timber building built with wooden slabs, columns, and beams (photo: Ema Peter (http://www.emapeter.com/)
Mass timber buildings are increasingly being built and have a number of environmental benefits. They are lighter than other common building materials like steel, are fire resistant, and their use reduces carbon dioxide emissions compared to other building materials. Buildings are even being constructed with beetle-killed wood to mitigate the impacts of forests disturbances on the carbon cycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much is too long a wait? Calculating expected wait times of wood deliveries</title>
      <link>/post/how-much-is-too-long-a-wait-calculating-expected-wait-times-of-wood-deliveries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-much-is-too-long-a-wait-calculating-expected-wait-times-of-wood-deliveries/</guid>
      <description>Logging trucks wait to be weighed before dropping off their loads of wood. (Photo: Jamey Malcomb/Pine Journal)
How important are wait times for loggers and truckers?Wood procurement managers and suppliers are both interested in reducing the wait times (or turn times) of wood deliveries. Wait times are defined as the time required for trucks to scale in and out when wood is delivered to a mill.
Both wood procurement managers and their suppliers need to know when wait times exceed the amount of time they expect.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>