<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on </title>
    <link>/events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R Statistical Software for Invasive Species Applications</title>
      <link>/events/r-statistical-software-for-invasive-species-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/r-statistical-software-for-invasive-species-applications/</guid>
      <description>Invasive species professionals are increasingly using data in new and complex ways. This hands-on workshop will provide an introduction to R software and how it can be used to acquire, analyze, and visualize invasive species data. This workshop will encourage and empower professionals to better use data to make strategic decisions about invasive species. It will be especially valuable to graduate students who are at an early stage in their programs and professionals seeking to learn about the software and how it can be used in their work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science for Forestry Applications</title>
      <link>/events/try2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/try2/</guid>
      <description>This hands-on workshop will showcase how data science can be used in forestry applications. Learn how to use open-source software (specifically R) to work quickly and efficiently with forestry data, with a focus on using large datasets such as Forest Inventory and Analysis data. This workshop is perfect for students and professionals who want to learn more about how to use R to work with the data they have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting down with pagedown</title>
      <link>/events/getting-down-with-pagedown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/getting-down-with-pagedown/</guid>
      <description>This is a presentation given to the Twin Cities R User Group on 17 Oct 2019 in Bloomington, MN. This presentation provides an introduction to using pagedown in R. pagedown creates and designs paged HTML documents from R using the R Markdown language. Think reading reports with data summaries embedded in them, all in an HTML format produced in R.
SlidesGithub repositoryExamples with pagedown</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>