<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science on </title>
    <link>/tags/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Random forests in a nutshell</title>
      <link>/post/random-forests-in-a-nutshell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/random-forests-in-a-nutshell/</guid>
      <description>Random forests have exploded in popularity in the forestry discipline in recent years. Random forests (RF) are a quantitative tool categorized as a machine learning technique. Analysts prefer to use RF methods because they can handle large amounts of data, provide the relative importance of a many variables, and can be applied to classification or regression problems.
The following graph shows the number of articles from four common journals in the forestry discipline that contained the term “random forests” in the article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>31 R packages for forest analysts</title>
      <link>/post/31-r-packages-for-forest-analysts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/31-r-packages-for-forest-analysts/</guid>
      <description>The R program is one of the most popular programs being used by forest analysts today. The power of R comes from its diversity of packages. A package is a collection of functions and data sets developed by R users.
The value of using R packages is that someone else might have already written a suite of functions for you. These can include your coworkers, colleagues, and other professionals. R packages are written to be collaborative so that they can be shared with others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do loggers feel? Sentiment analysis on the opinions of logging contractors</title>
      <link>/post/how-do-loggers-feel-sentiment-analysis-on-the-opinions-of-logging-contractors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-do-loggers-feel-sentiment-analysis-on-the-opinions-of-logging-contractors/</guid>
      <description>After we conduct a survey, we have a routine for analyzing the data. Summarize the numerical responses and report values like means for specific questions. Group the data into different demographics and report the means within these categories.
If we ask for any qualitative data through comments (e.g., “What is your opinion of X?”), the responses are always worth reading. We often get a lot of insight from reading an individual’s comments, and these comments can unveil new dimensions of our analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting your data into R from Google Sheets</title>
      <link>/post/getting-your-data-into-r-from-google-sheets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-your-data-into-r-from-google-sheets/</guid>
      <description>If you’re like me, more of the data you use on a daily basis are stored in Google Sheets. You might be using fewer Excel spreadsheets and .csv files. I recently researched the most up-to-date ways to import data from an Access database into R. (It had been a while since I imported data from a database.)
Using Google Sheets to store data has several advantages:
Multiple people can collaborate on the same data set,Information entered into a Google Form can populate data in a Google Spreadsheet,Data can be accessed and edited both online and offline, andGoogle Sheets can be converted to Excel spreadsheets, and vice versa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The three kinds of data scientists in forestry</title>
      <link>/post/the-three-kinds-of-data-scientists-in-forestry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-three-kinds-of-data-scientists-in-forestry/</guid>
      <description>Data scientists are highly sought after professionals across tens of thousands of companies. And there&amp;rsquo;s a difference between what a data scientist does and what a statistician does.
The field of statistics has been around for centuries, while data science programs at universities are just now beginning to graduate their first students.
In statistics, hypotheses are evaluated. In data science, hypotheses are generated. Statistics is often considered a primary data analysis technique, while data science is often considered secondary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science for Forestry Applications</title>
      <link>/events/try2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/try2/</guid>
      <description>This hands-on workshop will showcase how data science can be used in forestry applications. Learn how to use open-source software (specifically R) to work quickly and efficiently with forestry data, with a focus on using large datasets such as Forest Inventory and Analysis data. This workshop is perfect for students and professionals who want to learn more about how to use R to work with the data they have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New logging companies with old equipment: Finding patterns in logging businesses using clustering</title>
      <link>/post/new-logging-companies-with-old-equipment-finding-patterns-in-logging-businesses-using-clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/new-logging-companies-with-old-equipment-finding-patterns-in-logging-businesses-using-clustering/</guid>
      <description>Loggers are the backbone of the forest products industry and contribute to the 2.5 million jobs in the US that forests provide. Despite their importance to the industry, many studies have highlighted the challenges that loggers face with regard to economic markets, changing demographics, and an unhealthy outlook on the profession.
As an example in Minnesota, a recent study indicated that the average age of logging businesses continues to grow older, with a third of loggers more than 60 years old.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>