<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Statistics on </title>
    <link>/categories/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Statistics on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling in the tidyverse, an example predicting tree biomass</title>
      <link>/post/fit-many-models-with-broom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/fit-many-models-with-broom/</guid>
      <description>One of the most revolutionary advances in the last 10 years in the R program has been the tidyverse. I recently watched Hadley Wickham’s talk on the tidyverse from rstudio::conf 2020 and it was a great synopsis of the current status and future of the packages.
The growth of the tidyverse packages is astounding. As an example, the cumulative number of downloads for the dplyr package has reached over 10 million.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to determine accuracy of classification models (with forestry data)</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-determine-accuracy-of-classification-models-with-forestry-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-to-determine-accuracy-of-classification-models-with-forestry-data/</guid>
      <description>Classification is the process when you predict something, and that something is a class or label. It’s widely used when analyzing and modeling forestry data. Data scientists use if often as one of the many machine learning algorithms.
You might have learned about classification in the context of logistic regression. In logistic regression, your outcome is a binary class of data. For example, a tree can be alive or dead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruffed grouse and West Nile: A review of the binomial distribution</title>
      <link>/post/ruffed-grouse-and-west-nile-a-review-of-the-binomial-distribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ruffed-grouse-and-west-nile-a-review-of-the-binomial-distribution/</guid>
      <description>There’s been a lot of talk in the wildlife community about the West Nile virus and its impacts on ruffed grouse populations.
In 2018, a multi-state effort examined the presence of West Nile virus in ruffed grouse populations across the US Lake States. The study concluded that while the West Nile virus was present in the region, grouse that are exposed to West Nile do not always die and can survive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should foresters keep saying “statistically significant”?</title>
      <link>/post/should-foresters-keep-saying-statistically-significant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/should-foresters-keep-saying-statistically-significant/</guid>
      <description>The statistics community has had a lot of discussion in recent years about the role of p -values and statistical significance. What does this mean for forest biometricians and analysts that have traditionally used p -values and tests of significance in their daily work?
The American Statistical Association’s August 2019 edition of their magazine Significance has a number of great articles on significance. They even refer to the term as “the S word”:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Google Forms to analyze confidence intervals: a teaching statistics activity</title>
      <link>/post/using-google-forms-to-analyze-confidence-intervals-a-teaching-statistics-activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/using-google-forms-to-analyze-confidence-intervals-a-teaching-statistics-activity/</guid>
      <description>This post describes how the concepts of confidence intervals can be taught to students. The ideal participants are undergraduate students in an introductory statistics. The in-class activity reveals to students that most people are overconfident in their estimation of uncertainty. The activity uses the example of moose, a charismatic wildlife species in Minnesota.
IntroductionDemonstrations of data and statistical concepts are effective when they are designed with a structure that encourages participation in the classroom 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>