<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Forest products on </title>
    <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/categories/forest-products/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Forest products on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arbor-analytics.com/categories/forest-products/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Harvested wood products in the Forest Vegetation Simulator</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2022-04-23-harvested-wood-products-in-the-forest-vegetation-simulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2022-04-23-harvested-wood-products-in-the-forest-vegetation-simulator/</guid>
      <description>Carbon is stored and sequestered in growing forests. It can also can be stored “off site” in the form of harvested wood products. These can be in short-lived products (i.e., paper or pulp) or long-lived ones (i.e., utility poles).
Harvested wood products in use and solid waste disposal sites (e.g., landfills) represent 4.5% of the total amount of carbon in the US. When using wood products, lower emissions are used compared fossil fuel-intensive materials such as steel and concrete.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the forest products industry used Paycheck Protection Program loans (2022 update)</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2022-02-12-how-the-forest-products-industry-used-paycheck-protection-program-loans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2022-02-12-how-the-forest-products-industry-used-paycheck-protection-program-loans/</guid>
      <description>SummaryThe Paycheck Protection Program (PPP) offered loans to businesses to provide a direct incentive for them to keep their workers on payroll. Forest products companies across the US received $4.7 billion in PPP loans offered through the Small Business Administration. Over 35,000 loans were offered to forest products companies in the US from April 2020 through May 2021, affecting 487,000 workers in the forest industry.
The Paycheck Protection ProgramThe US Small Business Administration (SBA) managed the Paycheck Protection Program (PPP) between April 2020 and May 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timberlands as investments see biggest gain since 2014</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2022-01-22-visualizing-timberland-returns-in-the-last-10-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2022-01-22-visualizing-timberland-returns-in-the-last-10-years/</guid>
      <description>Forests and timberlands have long been popular investments that provide returns comparable to other economy-wide measures. The changing private ownership patterns in US forests over the last several decades, as timberlands have been owned or managed by timber investment management organizations or real estate investment trusts, has led to a rise in the benefits of timberland as an investment.
The National Council of Real Estate Investment Fiduciaries (NCREIF) recently posted fourth-quarter returns for their Timberland Index, an index representing 454 investment-grade timberland properties with a market value of $24 billion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The forest products industry’s use of Paycheck Protection Program loans</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-05-23-the-forest-products-industry-s-use-of-paycheck-protection-program-loans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-05-23-the-forest-products-industry-s-use-of-paycheck-protection-program-loans/</guid>
      <description>SummaryThe Paycheck Protection Program (PPP) offered loans to businesses to provide a direct incentive for them to keep their workers on payroll. Forest products companies across the US received $4.7 billion in PPP loans offered through the Small Business Administration. Over 34,000 loans were offered to forest products companies in the US from April 2020 through May 2021, affecting 485,000 workers in the forest industry.
The Paycheck Protection ProgramThe US Small Business Administration (SBA) managed the Paycheck Protection Program (PPP) between April 2020 and May 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
