<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>carbon credits on </title>
    <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/tags/carbon-credits/</link>
    <description>Recent content in carbon credits on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arbor-analytics.com/tags/carbon-credits/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Price of carbon in CARB decreases slightly</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2022-09-07-price-of-carbon-in-carb-decreases-slightly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2022-09-07-price-of-carbon-in-carb-decreases-slightly/</guid>
      <description>The price of carbon per metric tonne decreased slightly at a recent auction hosted by the California Air Resources Board (CARB). According to CARB’s recent Auction Information and Results from their auction on August 17, the settlement price of one metric tonne of carbon was $27.00. This represents a 12% decrease from prices of $30.85 posted in CARB’s last auction in May 2022.
I’ve been keeping track of the price of carbon at CARB auctions for some time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Price of carbon hits a new record high</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2022-06-03-price-of-carbon-hits-a-new-record-high/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2022-06-03-price-of-carbon-hits-a-new-record-high/</guid>
      <description>The price of carbon per metric tonne reached a record high at a recent auction hosted by the California Air Resources Board (CARB). According to CARB’s recent Auction Information and Results from May 2022, the settlement price of one metric tonne of carbon was $30.85. This represents a 9% increase from prices of $28.30 as recent as November 2021.
Auction reserve prices have increased marginally over the last several years, ranging from $14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carbon credits: quantity versus quality</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2022-04-10-carbon-credits-quantity-versus-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2022-04-10-carbon-credits-quantity-versus-quality/</guid>
      <description>The forestry community is focused on carbon, and the question of quantity versus quality of credits is increasingly being raised. Credits associated with forest carbon are bringing new opportunities to landowners and the investors that value timberlands.
With about 800 million acres of forests in the US alone, there is no lack of carbon for emerging markets to tap into. Some carbon programs are limited by not including public lands, but the volume of forests in other ownerships is large.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
