<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Economics on </title>
    <link>/tags/economics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Economics on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic contribution of forestry employees across US states</title>
      <link>/post/economic-contribution-of-forestry-employees-across-us-states/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/economic-contribution-of-forestry-employees-across-us-states/</guid>
      <description>The forest products industry relies on wood, a renewable and sustainable raw material. The industry is a top ten manufacturing employer. A few other insights on the importance of the forest products industry:
250 companies comprise the pulp, paper, and paperboard mill industry in the US,The US forest products industry generates 5% of the manufacturing GDP ($169 billion),The US forest products industry contains over 22,000 manufacturing facilities (~5,000 pulp and paper and 17,000 wood products)56% of US forests are privately owned by family forest owners and companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on the American Forestry Conference</title>
      <link>/post/reflections-on-the-american-forestry-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/reflections-on-the-american-forestry-conference/</guid>
      <description>Shawn Baker presents on trends in logging businesses.
Last week I tuned into the American Forestry Conference, a virtual conference on the forest products industry and how forestry businesses can reshape the future US economy. The conference, organized by the Georgia Forestry Association, had 35 speakers that discussed topics such as the challenges and opportunities of the role of forestry in the current and future economic climate. In an email, the organizing committee reported 540 attendees from 26 US states.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>