<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>forest inventory on </title>
    <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/tags/forest-inventory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in forest inventory on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arbor-analytics.com/tags/forest-inventory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Five R packages every forest analyst should be using</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2022-01-14-six-r-packages-every-forest-analysts-should-be-using/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2022-01-14-six-r-packages-every-forest-analysts-should-be-using/</guid>
      <description>The R program is one of the most popular programs being used by forest analysts today. Forest analysts use R packages, or collections of functions and data sets, to help guide their everyday work.
Last year I wrote about 31 R packages available to forest analysts available on the Comprehensive R Archive Network (CRAN) package repository. For perspective, as of today CRAN has archived 18,732 packages since 2006.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drought in the US West: impacts from the last ten years</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-07-23-drought-in-the-us-west-impacts-in-the-last-10-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-07-23-drought-in-the-us-west-impacts-in-the-last-10-years/</guid>
      <description>Drought conditions in the western US, 20 July 2021. From US Drought Monitor.
Much of the western United States is currently under severe drought conditions. Drought impacts trees and forests in the short and long term. Trees and forests can tolerate some extended dry periods depending of species and local conditions, but without adequate moisture availability, drought can ultimately lead to tree mortality.
Perhaps the greatest impact of drought is the stress it places on trees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forest carbon and short-lived trees</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/forest-carbon-markets-and-short-lived-trees/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/forest-carbon-markets-and-short-lived-trees/</guid>
      <description>I spoke with a forest products company representative this week who expressed concern with “extending rotations” so that carbon is locked up in trees for a longer time. Many forest carbon markets are proposing delaying harvesting for a few years so that more carbon accumulates over time.
The particular concern was in Minnesota where aspen, the state’s most commercially important species, is crucial to the forest products economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coverting forest inventory data from volume to carbon </title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/coverting-wood-scaled-as-weight-to-carbon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/coverting-wood-scaled-as-weight-to-carbon/</guid>
      <description>The amount of carbon in a forest is a key metric that decision-makers want to know. Accurate estimates of forest carbon are needed if a landowner is interested in enrolling a forest into carbon markets.
Unfortunately, most forest inventories continue to measure the amount of wood in a stand in terms of the volume it contains. Forest analysts also rely on historical forest inventory data to project future forest structure and composition - it is not unlikely to rely on inventory data that are more than 20 years old.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>States with the biggest gains in forest carbon over the last 30 years</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/states-with-the-biggest-gains-in-forest-carbon-over-the-last-30-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/states-with-the-biggest-gains-in-forest-carbon-over-the-last-30-years/</guid>
      <description>Trees and forests sequester carbon dioxide and other greenhouse gases from the atmosphere. This makes them a natural climate solution. This also encourages managers to quantify carbon attributes along with the myriad of other benefits that forests provide.
The value of carbon in forests has seen a tremendous increase in recent years. The increase in voluntary forest carbon markets have required analysts to have a better understanding of carbon attributes in the forests they work in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forest carbon stocks in every US state</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/carbon-by-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/carbon-by-state/</guid>
      <description>photo by Sean MacEntee
In April 2020, the USDA Forest Service published Greenhouse gas emissions and removals from forest land, woodlands, and urban trees in the United States, 1990-2018. What makes this annual report unique is that forest carbon estimates are reported for each US state. Data are available in an appendix which lists forest carbon stocks and flux for each state from 1990 to 2018.
Across the US, forests, urban trees, and harvested wood products are the largest carbon sink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polar area diagrams in celebration of Florence Nightingale</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/polar-area-diagrams-in-celebration-of-florence-nightingale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/polar-area-diagrams-in-celebration-of-florence-nightingale/</guid>
      <description>In 1858 the general public was familiar with seeing statistics presented in tables. Visualizations showing statistics and data were not widely used and were difficult to construct. One visualization that was shown to Queen Victoria in this year would live on and continue to be used in the 21st century.
The visualization showed the number of deaths from soldiers in the Crimean War, fought in the 1850s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to calculate carbon from board feet and cords</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/how-to-calculate-carbon-from-board-feet-and-cords/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/how-to-calculate-carbon-from-board-feet-and-cords/</guid>
      <description>Foresters and wood buyers are increasingly being asked about the amount of carbon that trees and forests store. However, foresters and wood buyers do not inventory or buy their wood on a carbon basis. Instead, forests in many regions of the US are inventoried and sold using volume measurements such as board feet and cords. If a forest resources professional knows how measurements like wood volume relate to carbon, he or she can feel empowered when discussing the importance of forests and forest management in the context of carbon with landowners and decision makers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disentagling the interactions between site index and disturbance</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/disentagling-the-interactions-between-site-index-and-disturbance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/disentagling-the-interactions-between-site-index-and-disturbance/</guid>
      <description>The Black Hills National Forest has been in the news recently after completing a timber sustainability report. In recent years, the Black Hills was one of the US Forest Service’s greatest timber-producing National Forests in the country.
Much of the increase in timber harvest in recent years at the Black Hills National Forest was in response to a deadly mountain pine beetle epidemic. As a result, the new report suggests that current timber harvests are not sustainable into the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Units in forest carbon numbers: a primer</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/units-in-forest-carbon-numbers-a-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/units-in-forest-carbon-numbers-a-primer/</guid>
      <description>Forest analysts are increasingly being asked about the amount of carbon that trees and forests store. However, most analysts are trained in summarizing forestry data sets to obtain measurements such as volume and basal area.
If a forest analyst knows how to “speak carbon”, this can leave them feeling empowered when discussing the importance of forests and forest management in the context of carbon. This can leave a solid impression with landowners and decision makers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which forest biometrics researchers get the most citations?</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/which-forest-biometrics-faculty-get-the-most-citations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/which-forest-biometrics-faculty-get-the-most-citations/</guid>
      <description>Researchers in the forest and natural resource sciences are measured by their productivity: how many publications they write and how many times those publications are cited by other researchers. Researchers that have many publications that are cited in the literature by others generally have rewarding careers and are promoted.
In 2017 I wrote a blog post for the Ecological Society of America’s Early Career Ecologist section that provided some evidence that early-career scientists publish earlier in their careers compared to more senior researchers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A 50-year history of forest measurements by analyzing Forest Measurements</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/a-50-year-history-of-forest-measurements-by-analyzing-forest-measurements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/a-50-year-history-of-forest-measurements-by-analyzing-forest-measurements/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve even taken a course in forest measurements, you likely used Forest Measurements as the textbook. The first edition of forest measurements was published in 1967 by Thomas Eugene Avery and included a number of topics related to forest inventory, sampling forest resources, and tree and stand measurements.
The book recently published its 6th edition in 2018 and is available through Waveland Press. Investigating how the book has incorporated new topics gives insights into the advances of the field of forest measurements:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quickly explore your timber cruise data with six lines of code</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/explore-your-timber-cruise-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/explore-your-timber-cruise-data/</guid>
      <description>Data from timber cruises and other forest inventories need to be clean and easy to interpret. Time can be lost in the field and office if data were collected sloppily, were measured in the field without a protocol, or are otherwise “messy” with lots of errors.
A data-checking routine can save time, money, and resources. Identifying potential data inaccuracies or inconsistencies soon after they’re collected can help eliminate any inappropriate decisions that are made from those data further down the line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How many trees make a mass timber building?</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/how-many-trees-make-a-mass-timber-building/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/how-many-trees-make-a-mass-timber-building/</guid>
      <description>The T3 in Minneapolis, Minnesota is a mass timber building built with wooden slabs, columns, and beams (photo: Ema Peter (http://www.emapeter.com/)
Mass timber buildings are increasingly being built and have a number of environmental benefits. They are lighter than other common building materials like steel, are fire resistant, and their use reduces carbon dioxide emissions compared to other building materials. Buildings are even being constructed with beetle-killed wood to mitigate the impacts of forests disturbances on the carbon cycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stratified vs. simple random sampling: fun with forestsamplr</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/stratified-vs-simple-random-sampling-fun-with-forestsamplr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/stratified-vs-simple-random-sampling-fun-with-forestsamplr/</guid>
      <description>Tools for estimating population means for stratified and simple random samplesIf we know the size of a number of subpopulations that are a part of a larger population, we can use stratified random sampling to come up with a more precise estimate of a population mean. If these subpopulations, or strata, have different mean values and smaller variances relative to the population mean, stratified random sampling is generally preferred over simple random sampling.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
