<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Logging on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/categories/logging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Logging on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/categories/logging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Comparing logging trucker wages to other industries</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-08-15-comparing-logging-trucker-wages-to-other-trucking-industries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-08-15-comparing-logging-trucker-wages-to-other-trucking-industries/</guid>
      <description>Log truck (photo: Darin Oswald)&#xA;“To solve any problem in forestry, first figure out where the roads will go.”&#xA;That’s a quote I’ve heard a retired university professor tell students a number of times. There is a lot of wisdom in it: many forest resources are located in remote areas. Hauling products from the woods to the mill can be challenging. The economics of utilizing wood becomes less appealing if forest products are located far away from the mill that processes it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the logging industry in the Lake States used PPP loans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-03-22-how-the-logging-industry-in-the-lake-states-used-ppp-loans/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-03-22-how-the-logging-industry-in-the-lake-states-used-ppp-loans/</guid>
      <description>Logging companies in the US Lake States requested $49.7 million in Paycheck Protection Program loans offered through the Small Business Administration in 2020 and 2021. These loans were offered to 1,445 logging businesses in the Lake States.&#xA;The SBA Paycheck Protection Program provides information on PPP loan distributions to businesses throughout the COVID-19 pandemic. Depending on the size of the business and its needs, loan amounts varied.&#xA;For all logging businesses, the average loan amount was $34,412 and there were an average of 3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maine logging industry&#39;s use of PPP loans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-01-23-maine-logging-industry-s-use-of-ppp-loans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-01-23-maine-logging-industry-s-use-of-ppp-loans/</guid>
      <description>Logging companies in Maine requested at least $13.8 million in Paycheck Protection Program loans offered through the Small Business Administration in 2020. These loans were offered to 256 logging businesses in Maine in the spring and early summer of 2020.&#xA;The SBA Paycheck Protection Program Loan Level Data provides information on PPP loan distributions to businesses made through August 8, 2020. Depending on the size of the business and its needs, loan amounts varied.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
