<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ggplot2 on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/tags/ggplot2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ggplot2 on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/tags/ggplot2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Four ways to supercharge your scatterplots</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/four-ways-to-supercharge-your-scatterplots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/four-ways-to-supercharge-your-scatterplots/</guid>
      <description>Scatterplots are a go-to visualization with forestry data. Scatterplots show the relationship between two quantitative variables measured on the same object. For example, a tree’s diameter and height.&#xA;There are a few rules for all scatterplots:&#xA;The explanatory variable goes on the x-axis. (This is usually the “easier” measurement to collect.)&#xD;The response variable goes on the y-axis. (This is usually the “harder” measurement to collect.)&#xD;Each observation is a point on the graph.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding some music to boxplots, and better ways to visualize diameter distributions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/better-ways-to-visualize-multi-modal-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/better-ways-to-visualize-multi-modal-data/</guid>
      <description>Boxplots are an old standby in statistics and data analysis. They became popular because they show the distribution of a data set along with a clear visualization of its five-number summary: the minimum, first quartile, median, third quartile and maximum. But how can we unpack what’s going on between those boxes and whiskers?&#xA;Some forestry data: In the examples below, I’ve used tree diameters measured in four management units at the Penobscot Experimental Forest in Maine.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
