<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on </title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using clustering with logging industry data</title>
      <link>/post/using-clustering-with-logging-industry-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/using-clustering-with-logging-industry-data/</guid>
      <description>A forest products company may not always require a precise numeric answer to solve a problem. Oftentimes, understanding a pattern and how data are clustered can suffice.
The benefit of using pattern recognition techniques is that data need not be labeled prior to analyzing them. In contrast to statistical techniques like regression and classification, identifying patterns can unearth new trends in how data are arranged in your organization.
Clustering is an unsupervised ML algorithm that groups items.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polar area diagrams in celebration of Florence Nightingale</title>
      <link>/post/polar-area-diagrams-in-celebration-of-florence-nightingale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/polar-area-diagrams-in-celebration-of-florence-nightingale/</guid>
      <description>In 1858 the general public was familiar with seeing statistics presented in tables. Visualizations showing statistics and data were not widely used and were difficult to construct. One visualization that was shown to Queen Victoria in this year would live on and continue to be used in the 21st century.
The visualization showed the number of deaths from soldiers in the Crimean War, fought in the 1850s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do loggers feel? Sentiment analysis on the opinions of logging contractors</title>
      <link>/post/how-do-loggers-feel-sentiment-analysis-on-the-opinions-of-logging-contractors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-do-loggers-feel-sentiment-analysis-on-the-opinions-of-logging-contractors/</guid>
      <description>After we conduct a survey, we have a routine for analyzing the data. Summarize the numerical responses and report values like means for specific questions. Group the data into different demographics and report the means within these categories.
If we ask for any qualitative data through comments (e.g., “What is your opinion of X?”), the responses are always worth reading. We often get a lot of insight from reading an individual’s comments, and these comments can unveil new dimensions of our analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting your data into R from Google Sheets</title>
      <link>/post/getting-your-data-into-r-from-google-sheets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-your-data-into-r-from-google-sheets/</guid>
      <description>If you’re like me, more of the data you use on a daily basis are stored in Google Sheets. You might be using fewer Excel spreadsheets and .csv files. I recently researched the most up-to-date ways to import data from an Access database into R. (It had been a while since I imported data from a database.)
Using Google Sheets to store data has several advantages:
Multiple people can collaborate on the same data set,Information entered into a Google Form can populate data in a Google Spreadsheet,Data can be accessed and edited both online and offline, andGoogle Sheets can be converted to Excel spreadsheets, and vice versa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attention forestry researchers: Incorporate a call-to-action in your presentations</title>
      <link>/post/attention-forestry-researchers-incorporate-a-call-to-action-in-your-presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/attention-forestry-researchers-incorporate-a-call-to-action-in-your-presentations/</guid>
      <description>A simple call-to-action to use in a presentation: link to the slides you just presented.)
“The primary purpose of a talk is advertising, not science.”
This is one of the statements made in the Leek group guide to giving talks. Our lab group discussed this topic at a recent meeting in April.
Sometimes we are required in a grant to provide a talk via a presentation about our research to the public.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to calculate carbon from board feet and cords</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-calculate-carbon-from-board-feet-and-cords/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-to-calculate-carbon-from-board-feet-and-cords/</guid>
      <description>Foresters and wood buyers are increasingly being asked about the amount of carbon that trees and forests store. However, foresters and wood buyers do not inventory or buy their wood on a carbon basis. Instead, forests in many regions of the US are inventoried and sold using volume measurements such as board feet and cords. If a forest resources professional knows how measurements like wood volume relate to carbon, he or she can feel empowered when discussing the importance of forests and forest management in the context of carbon with landowners and decision makers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disentagling the interactions between site index and disturbance</title>
      <link>/post/disentagling-the-interactions-between-site-index-and-disturbance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/disentagling-the-interactions-between-site-index-and-disturbance/</guid>
      <description>The Black Hills National Forest has been in the news recently after completing a timber sustainability report. In recent years, the Black Hills was one of the US Forest Service’s greatest timber-producing National Forests in the country.
Much of the increase in timber harvest in recent years at the Black Hills National Forest was in response to a deadly mountain pine beetle epidemic. As a result, the new report suggests that current timber harvests are not sustainable into the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forest carbon cheat sheet</title>
      <link>/post/forest-carbon-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/forest-carbon-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>The Forest Carbon Cheat Sheet is a quick reference guide for converting forest carbon measurements and understanding typical carbon values at the tree, stand, and landscape levels.
The Cheast Sheet is updated with the most recent values published in the US Environmental Protection Agency Inventory of U.S. Greenhouse Gas Emissions and Sinks: 1990-2018.
DOWNLOAD (PDF)
DOWNLOAD (JPEG)
The Forest Carbon Cheat Sheet.
If you have questions or comments on the Cheat Sheet, email Matt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The decline of researchers in forest science</title>
      <link>/post/the-decline-of-researchers-in-forest-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-decline-of-researchers-in-forest-science/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago during a coffee break in a day-long meeting, I was asked by a forester that works for a state agency to connect him with some contacts. He was interested in anyone that works in the forest industry in Minnesota that “does research”.
I work as a faculty member and Extension forester at a Society of American Foresters-accredited institution. I am generally knowledgeable about current forestry research and the people doing it in our state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling in the tidyverse, an example predicting tree biomass</title>
      <link>/post/fit-many-models-with-broom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/fit-many-models-with-broom/</guid>
      <description>One of the most revolutionary advances in the last 10 years in the R program has been the tidyverse. I recently watched Hadley Wickham’s talk on the tidyverse from rstudio::conf 2020 and it was a great synopsis of the current status and future of the packages.
The growth of the tidyverse packages is astounding. As an example, the cumulative number of downloads for the dplyr package has reached over 10 million.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>H-2B guest workers in forestry: by the numbers</title>
      <link>/post/h-2b-forestry-and-conservation-workers-by-the-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/h-2b-forestry-and-conservation-workers-by-the-numbers/</guid>
      <description>Guest workers regenerating a northern Minnesota forest. (photo: @Chris_KTDunham, Twitter)
Guest workers hired through the H-2B visa program get jobs done. This is especially true across many forestry companies. Guest workers plant trees, conduct silvicultural treatments, and assist in tree nursery production.
A strong guest worker program can lead to a future forest products industry that is healthy and sustainable in the long term.
Last week, the Trump administration announced 35,000 additional seasonal H-2B guest worker visas available in 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Units in forest carbon numbers: a primer</title>
      <link>/post/units-in-forest-carbon-numbers-a-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/units-in-forest-carbon-numbers-a-primer/</guid>
      <description>Forest analysts are increasingly being asked about the amount of carbon that trees and forests store. However, most analysts are trained in summarizing forestry data sets to obtain measurements such as volume and basal area.
If a forest analyst knows how to “speak carbon”, this can leave them feeling empowered when discussing the importance of forests and forest management in the context of carbon. This can leave a solid impression with landowners and decision makers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much carbon is stored in one trillion trees?</title>
      <link>/post/how-much-carbon-is-stored-in-a-trillion-trees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-much-carbon-is-stored-in-a-trillion-trees/</guid>
      <description>The short answer: About 5.7 times as much than is currently stored in forests in the lower 48 US states and Alaska. One trillion trees equates to about 101 billion metric tons of carbon stored.The Trillion Trees Campaign has been widespread in the news recently. The United States has committed to the initiative, announced at the World Economic Forum in January 2020 and mentioned during President Trump’s annual State of the Union address on 4 February 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four ways to supercharge your scatterplots</title>
      <link>/post/four-ways-to-supercharge-your-scatterplots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/four-ways-to-supercharge-your-scatterplots/</guid>
      <description>Scatterplots are a go-to visualization with forestry data. Scatterplots show the relationship between two quantitative variables measured on the same object. For example, a tree’s diameter and height.
There are a few rules for all scatterplots:
The explanatory variable goes on the x-axis. (This is usually the “easier” measurement to collect.)The response variable goes on the y-axis. (This is usually the “harder” measurement to collect.)Each observation is a point on the graph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to determine accuracy of classification models (with forestry data)</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-determine-accuracy-of-classification-models-with-forestry-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-to-determine-accuracy-of-classification-models-with-forestry-data/</guid>
      <description>Classification is the process when you predict something, and that something is a class or label. It’s widely used when analyzing and modeling forestry data. Data scientists use if often as one of the many machine learning algorithms.
You might have learned about classification in the context of logistic regression. In logistic regression, your outcome is a binary class of data. For example, a tree can be alive or dead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The three kinds of data scientists in forestry</title>
      <link>/post/the-three-kinds-of-data-scientists-in-forestry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-three-kinds-of-data-scientists-in-forestry/</guid>
      <description>Data scientists are highly sought after professionals across tens of thousands of companies. And there&amp;rsquo;s a difference between what a data scientist does and what a statistician does.
The field of statistics has been around for centuries, while data science programs at universities are just now beginning to graduate their first students.
In statistics, hypotheses are evaluated. In data science, hypotheses are generated. Statistics is often considered a primary data analysis technique, while data science is often considered secondary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which forest biometrics researchers get the most citations?</title>
      <link>/post/which-forest-biometrics-faculty-get-the-most-citations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/which-forest-biometrics-faculty-get-the-most-citations/</guid>
      <description>Researchers in the forest and natural resource sciences are measured by their productivity: how many publications they write and how many times those publications are cited by other researchers. Researchers that have many publications that are cited in the literature by others generally have rewarding careers and are promoted.
In 2017 I wrote a blog post for the Ecological Society of America’s Early Career Ecologist section that provided some evidence that early-career scientists publish earlier in their careers compared to more senior researchers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruffed grouse and West Nile: A review of the binomial distribution</title>
      <link>/post/ruffed-grouse-and-west-nile-a-review-of-the-binomial-distribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ruffed-grouse-and-west-nile-a-review-of-the-binomial-distribution/</guid>
      <description>There’s been a lot of talk in the wildlife community about the West Nile virus and its impacts on ruffed grouse populations.
In 2018, a multi-state effort examined the presence of West Nile virus in ruffed grouse populations across the US Lake States. The study concluded that while the West Nile virus was present in the region, grouse that are exposed to West Nile do not always die and can survive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to created paged HTML documents with pagedown</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-created-paged-html-documents-with-pagedown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-to-created-paged-html-documents-with-pagedown/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to reading documents and data summaries online, HTML is often preferred over PDF. HTML documents are more interactive, easier to read on screens, and more accessible than PDFs.
Many R users that produce reproducible reports have used R Markdown for integrating text, images, code, and tables and figures into an HTML format. Using the R Markdown language allows R users to work within the R ecosystem for writing and producing code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to calculate how much carbon is in a tree</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-calculate-how-much-carbon-is-in-a-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-to-calculate-how-much-carbon-is-in-a-tree/</guid>
      <description>Carbon is perhaps the most important attribute in trees today. Forests in the United States sequester about 11% of the total CO2 emissions every year, making them an important tool to combat future global changes. Having accurate models that represent how much carbon is stored in trees is essential for understanding their carbon sequestration potential and are widely used in forest carbon accounting tools.
Most equations that predict the amount carbon in a tree start with first predicting its biomass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A 50-year history of forest measurements by analyzing Forest Measurements</title>
      <link>/post/a-50-year-history-of-forest-measurements-by-analyzing-forest-measurements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/a-50-year-history-of-forest-measurements-by-analyzing-forest-measurements/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve even taken a course in forest measurements, you likely used Forest Measurements as the textbook. The first edition of forest measurements was published in 1967 by Thomas Eugene Avery and included a number of topics related to forest inventory, sampling forest resources, and tree and stand measurements.
The book recently published its 6th edition in 2018 and is available through Waveland Press. Investigating how the book has incorporated new topics gives insights into the advances of the field of forest measurements:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should foresters keep saying “statistically significant”?</title>
      <link>/post/should-foresters-keep-saying-statistically-significant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/should-foresters-keep-saying-statistically-significant/</guid>
      <description>The statistics community has had a lot of discussion in recent years about the role of p -values and statistical significance. What does this mean for forest biometricians and analysts that have traditionally used p -values and tests of significance in their daily work?
The American Statistical Association’s August 2019 edition of their magazine Significance has a number of great articles on significance. They even refer to the term as “the S word”:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quickly explore your timber cruise data with six lines of code</title>
      <link>/post/explore-your-timber-cruise-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/explore-your-timber-cruise-data/</guid>
      <description>Data from timber cruises and other forest inventories need to be clean and easy to interpret. Time can be lost in the field and office if data were collected sloppily, were measured in the field without a protocol, or are otherwise “messy” with lots of errors.
A data-checking routine can save time, money, and resources. Identifying potential data inaccuracies or inconsistencies soon after they’re collected can help eliminate any inappropriate decisions that are made from those data further down the line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New logging companies with old equipment: Finding patterns in logging businesses using clustering</title>
      <link>/post/new-logging-companies-with-old-equipment-finding-patterns-in-logging-businesses-using-clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/new-logging-companies-with-old-equipment-finding-patterns-in-logging-businesses-using-clustering/</guid>
      <description>Loggers are the backbone of the forest products industry and contribute to the 2.5 million jobs in the US that forests provide. Despite their importance to the industry, many studies have highlighted the challenges that loggers face with regard to economic markets, changing demographics, and an unhealthy outlook on the profession.
As an example in Minnesota, a recent study indicated that the average age of logging businesses continues to grow older, with a third of loggers more than 60 years old.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Google Forms to analyze confidence intervals: a teaching statistics activity</title>
      <link>/post/using-google-forms-to-analyze-confidence-intervals-a-teaching-statistics-activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/using-google-forms-to-analyze-confidence-intervals-a-teaching-statistics-activity/</guid>
      <description>This post describes how the concepts of confidence intervals can be taught to students. The ideal participants are undergraduate students in an introductory statistics. The in-class activity reveals to students that most people are overconfident in their estimation of uncertainty. The activity uses the example of moose, a charismatic wildlife species in Minnesota.
IntroductionDemonstrations of data and statistical concepts are effective when they are designed with a structure that encourages participation in the classroom 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making animated GIFs in R: ten years of emerald ash borer spread in Minnesota </title>
      <link>/post/making-animated-gif-maps-in-r-visualizing-ten-years-of-emerald-ash-borer-spread-in-minnesota/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/making-animated-gif-maps-in-r-visualizing-ten-years-of-emerald-ash-borer-spread-in-minnesota/</guid>
      <description>The popularity of GIFs have exploded in recent years and they give photojournalists a great way to tell a story. Sometimes the right GIF image can bring data to life.
The general process to make a GIF image with maps in R is:
1. Create the images you want (e.g., using ggplot),
2. Stitch the images together with magick, and
3. Write the images as a GIF and share!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How many trees make a mass timber building?</title>
      <link>/post/how-many-trees-make-a-mass-timber-building/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-many-trees-make-a-mass-timber-building/</guid>
      <description>The T3 in Minneapolis, Minnesota is a mass timber building built with wooden slabs, columns, and beams (photo: Ema Peter (http://www.emapeter.com/)
Mass timber buildings are increasingly being built and have a number of environmental benefits. They are lighter than other common building materials like steel, are fire resistant, and their use reduces carbon dioxide emissions compared to other building materials. Buildings are even being constructed with beetle-killed wood to mitigate the impacts of forests disturbances on the carbon cycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much is too long a wait? Calculating expected wait times of wood deliveries</title>
      <link>/post/how-much-is-too-long-a-wait-calculating-expected-wait-times-of-wood-deliveries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-much-is-too-long-a-wait-calculating-expected-wait-times-of-wood-deliveries/</guid>
      <description>Logging trucks wait to be weighed before dropping off their loads of wood. (Photo: Jamey Malcomb/Pine Journal)
How important are wait times for loggers and truckers?Wood procurement managers and suppliers are both interested in reducing the wait times (or turn times) of wood deliveries. Wait times are defined as the time required for trucks to scale in and out when wood is delivered to a mill.
Both wood procurement managers and their suppliers need to know when wait times exceed the amount of time they expect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stratified vs. simple random sampling: fun with forestsamplr</title>
      <link>/post/stratified-vs-simple-random-sampling-fun-with-forestsamplr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/stratified-vs-simple-random-sampling-fun-with-forestsamplr/</guid>
      <description>Tools for estimating population means for stratified and simple random samplesIf we know the size of a number of subpopulations that are a part of a larger population, we can use stratified random sampling to come up with a more precise estimate of a population mean. If these subpopulations, or strata, have different mean values and smaller variances relative to the population mean, stratified random sampling is generally preferred over simple random sampling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecticut harvests almost as many deer with cars as their hunters do</title>
      <link>/post/deer-vehicle-accidents/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/deer-vehicle-accidents/</guid>
      <description>White-tailed deer provide a huge contribution to the outdoors economy and deer hunters support conservation efforts throughout the US. Despite the popularity and traditions of deer and deer hunting, they present a number of ecological problems including damage to forest and agricultural crops and landscaping. Deer are ravaging Long Island’s forests and in my own state of Minnesota we’ve started a citizen science program on monitoring the impacts of deer on forest vegetation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presenting regression results better with forest plots</title>
      <link>/post/presenting-regression-results-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/presenting-regression-results-better/</guid>
      <description>I was inspired by Sara Richter’s presentation at the 2019 Conference on Statistical Practice titled “Easy Ways to Make Data Visualizations More Effective”. One of the themes I took away from Sara’s presentation was that data visualization needs to be practiced, but good data visualization doesn’t need to be difficult to be done well.
When presenting results from a regression, people often use tables. While this is good if we need the true value of something, tables may not be good if we seek to convey general trends in our results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding some music to boxplots, and better ways to visualize diameter distributions</title>
      <link>/post/better-ways-to-visualize-multi-modal-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/better-ways-to-visualize-multi-modal-data/</guid>
      <description>Boxplots are an old standby in statistics and data analysis. They became popular because they show the distribution of a data set along with a clear visualization of its five-number summary: the minimum, first quartile, median, third quartile and maximum. But how can we unpack what’s going on between those boxes and whiskers?
Some forestry data: In the examples below, I’ve used tree diameters measured in four management units at the Penobscot Experimental Forest in Maine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spreading and gathering tree data</title>
      <link>/post/spreading-and-gathering-tree-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/spreading-and-gathering-tree-data/</guid>
      <description>A student emailed this week with a data management need: how to turn thousands of rows of data to make a calculation based on two time periods? In short, the data were in a long format and needed to be wide.
The experiment was something like this: the student had data containing the number of tree seedlings in a forest, measured in eight different plots. She revisited the same forest five years later and measured the number of seedlings again.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>