<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on </title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R Statistical Software for Invasive Species Applications</title>
      <link>/events/r-statistical-software-for-invasive-species-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/r-statistical-software-for-invasive-species-applications/</guid>
      <description>Invasive species professionals are increasingly using data in new and complex ways. This hands-on workshop will provide an introduction to R software and how it can be used to acquire, analyze, and visualize invasive species data. This workshop will encourage and empower professionals to better use data to make strategic decisions about invasive species. It will be especially valuable to graduate students who are at an early stage in their programs and professionals seeking to learn about the software and how it can be used in their work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>31 R packages for forest analysts</title>
      <link>/post/31-r-packages-for-forest-analysts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/31-r-packages-for-forest-analysts/</guid>
      <description>The R program is one of the most popular programs being used by forest analysts today. The power of R comes from its diversity of packages. A package is a collection of functions and data sets developed by R users.
The value of using R packages is that someone else might have already written a suite of functions for you. These can include your coworkers, colleagues, and other professionals. R packages are written to be collaborative so that they can be shared with others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forget spreading and gathering your R data, try pivoting instead</title>
      <link>/post/forget-spreading-and-gathering-your-r-data-try-pivoting-instead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/forget-spreading-and-gathering-your-r-data-try-pivoting-instead/</guid>
      <description>Reshaping data from a wide to a long format, or vice versa, is one of the most common data manipulation tasks that analysts need to do. One of my first posts on this blog was on how to do this in R.
That post highlighted the spread() and gather() functions available from the tidyr package. As it turns out, the gather() and spread() functions are still available to use but are no longer under active development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science for Forestry Applications</title>
      <link>/events/try2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/try2/</guid>
      <description>This hands-on workshop will showcase how data science can be used in forestry applications. Learn how to use open-source software (specifically R) to work quickly and efficiently with forestry data, with a focus on using large datasets such as Forest Inventory and Analysis data. This workshop is perfect for students and professionals who want to learn more about how to use R to work with the data they have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting down with pagedown</title>
      <link>/events/getting-down-with-pagedown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/getting-down-with-pagedown/</guid>
      <description>This is a presentation given to the Twin Cities R User Group on 17 Oct 2019 in Bloomington, MN. This presentation provides an introduction to using pagedown in R. pagedown creates and designs paged HTML documents from R using the R Markdown language. Think reading reports with data summaries embedded in them, all in an HTML format produced in R.
SlidesGithub repositoryExamples with pagedown</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to created paged HTML documents with pagedown</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-created-paged-html-documents-with-pagedown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-to-created-paged-html-documents-with-pagedown/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to reading documents and data summaries online, HTML is often preferred over PDF. HTML documents are more interactive, easier to read on screens, and more accessible than PDFs.
Many R users that produce reproducible reports have used R Markdown for integrating text, images, code, and tables and figures into an HTML format. Using the R Markdown language allows R users to work within the R ecosystem for writing and producing code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making animated GIFs in R: ten years of emerald ash borer spread in Minnesota </title>
      <link>/post/making-animated-gif-maps-in-r-visualizing-ten-years-of-emerald-ash-borer-spread-in-minnesota/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/making-animated-gif-maps-in-r-visualizing-ten-years-of-emerald-ash-borer-spread-in-minnesota/</guid>
      <description>The popularity of GIFs have exploded in recent years and they give photojournalists a great way to tell a story. Sometimes the right GIF image can bring data to life.
The general process to make a GIF image with maps in R is:
1. Create the images you want (e.g., using ggplot),
2. Stitch the images together with magick, and
3. Write the images as a GIF and share!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding some music to boxplots, and better ways to visualize diameter distributions</title>
      <link>/post/better-ways-to-visualize-multi-modal-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/better-ways-to-visualize-multi-modal-data/</guid>
      <description>Boxplots are an old standby in statistics and data analysis. They became popular because they show the distribution of a data set along with a clear visualization of its five-number summary: the minimum, first quartile, median, third quartile and maximum. But how can we unpack what’s going on between those boxes and whiskers?
Some forestry data: In the examples below, I’ve used tree diameters measured in four management units at the Penobscot Experimental Forest in Maine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spreading and gathering tree data</title>
      <link>/post/spreading-and-gathering-tree-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/spreading-and-gathering-tree-data/</guid>
      <description>A student emailed this week with a data management need: how to turn thousands of rows of data to make a calculation based on two time periods? In short, the data were in a long format and needed to be wide.
The experiment was something like this: the student had data containing the number of tree seedlings in a forest, measured in eight different plots. She revisited the same forest five years later and measured the number of seedlings again.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>