<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mixed Models on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/tags/mixed-models/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mixed Models on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/tags/mixed-models/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Linear quantile mixed models: applications in forestry</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-07-31-linear-quantile-mixed-models-applications-in-forestry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-07-31-linear-quantile-mixed-models-applications-in-forestry/</guid>
      <description>Example output comparing predictions from three models fit with linear quantile mixed models and one fit using ordinary least squares.&#xD;Mixed models have been used for decades by forest biometricians and statisticians. They have become popular because forestry and natural resources data are often nested, allowing the analyst to account for spatial and temporal correlation among measurements. Forest plots are often measured within stands, stands are located within ownerships, and a collection of ownerships comprise a landscape.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mixed models in R: a primer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/mixed-models-a-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/mixed-models-a-primer/</guid>
      <description>Myself and a team of coauthors recently submitted a manuscript that analyzed forest composition data from a silvicultural study. Here is a comment from a peer reviewer that reviewed the work:&#xA;“I would like the authors to justify not using mixed models or to change their analyses for mixed models.”&#xA;The comment urged us to reevaluate the analysis of the data. Ultimately we redid the analysis using a mixed model framework, instead of using the traditional analysis of variance approach taught in many introductory statistics classes.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
