<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Analytics on </title>
    <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/categories/analytics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Analytics on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arbor-analytics.com/categories/analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New updates for tools that query Forest Inventory and Analysis data</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2022-11-23-new-updates-for-tools-that-query-forest-inventory-and-analysis-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2022-11-23-new-updates-for-tools-that-query-forest-inventory-and-analysis-data/</guid>
      <description>The US national forest inventory has information contained from over 130,000 forest inventory plots across the country. Data collected and maintained by the Forest Inventory and Analysis (FIA) program are needed for answering core forestry questions, and having the right tools to help extract specific data that fits the analysis is essential.
After attending the FIA Science Stakeholder Meeting last week, I was happy to learn about some important updates to two tools that are widely used by forest analysts: the FIA EVALIDator program and the FIA DataMart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to spot poor data analyses</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2022-10-20-how-to-spot-poor-data-analyses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2022-10-20-how-to-spot-poor-data-analyses/</guid>
      <description>Being an excellent data analyst requires you to understand the techniques that go into analyzing data and how to communicate them effectively. While having a foundation in statistics and the quantitative sciences is essential, the most effective data analysts communicate information that influences decision makers.
Unfortunately, there are plenty of examples of sloppy data analyses that distort the reality of what data can tell us. As an example, genetics researchers have found that Microsoft Excel’s autocorrecting feature had led to errors in 30% of gene list observations over a six year span.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pandemic assistance to the forest industry: a summary</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/events/2022-09-27-pandemic-assistance-to-the-forest-industry-a-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/events/2022-09-27-pandemic-assistance-to-the-forest-industry-a-summary/</guid>
      <description>Forest products and timber harvesting and hauling businesses secured nearly $5 billion of federal funds through the Paycheck Protection Program and Pandemic Assistance to Timber Harvesters and Haulers programs to combat economic challenges presented by the COVID-19 pandemic. These slides were presented at the 2022 Society of American Foresters Convention in Baltimore, MD.
READ THE SLIDES.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading in data quickly into R</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2022-05-19-reading-in-data-quickly-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2022-05-19-reading-in-data-quickly-in-r/</guid>
      <description>If you’re like me, you work with a lot of data files in your daily analytical work. Despite the increase in cloud computing, reading in files locally to the machine your working on is common.
You want a rapid summary of your data and don’t want to wait forever for your computer to read in the file you’re working with. To do this, you want to use functions that are efficient and effective for working with large amounts of data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five R packages every forest analyst should be using</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2022-01-14-six-r-packages-every-forest-analysts-should-be-using/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2022-01-14-six-r-packages-every-forest-analysts-should-be-using/</guid>
      <description>The R program is one of the most popular programs being used by forest analysts today. Forest analysts use R packages, or collections of functions and data sets, to help guide their everyday work.
Last year I wrote about 31 R packages available to forest analysts available on the Comprehensive R Archive Network (CRAN) package repository. For perspective, as of today CRAN has archived 18,732 packages since 2006.
R users also make packages available on GitHub, particularly for specific disciplines like forest inventory and measurements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random forests: a tutorial with forestry data</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-09-26-random-forests-a-tutorial-with-forestry-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-09-26-random-forests-a-tutorial-with-forestry-data/</guid>
      <description>Random forests have quickly become one of the most popular analytical techniques used in forestry today. Random forests (RF) are a machine learning technique that differ in many ways to traditional prediction models such as regression. Random forests can handle a lot of data, can be applied to classification or regression problems, and rank the relative importance of many variables that are related to a response variable of interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The importance of citizen data scientists in forest analytics</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-09-07-the-importance-of-citizen-data-scientists-in-forest-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-09-07-the-importance-of-citizen-data-scientists-in-forest-analytics/</guid>
      <description>As a part of my work with the University of Minnesota Extension, we run the Assessing Vegetation Impacts from Deer program. The AVID program engages citizen scientists to monitor tree seedlings that are susceptible to browse from white-tailed deer. With little information on deer browse impacts for most of Minnesota’s tree species, the data are beginning to provide insights on how deer browse degrades the health of the forest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the forest products industry using NAICS codes</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-05-08-understanding-the-forest-products-industry-using-naics-codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-05-08-understanding-the-forest-products-industry-using-naics-codes/</guid>
      <description>To understand any industry, an analyst should be well acquainted with the codes designating the North American Industry Classification Systems. These NAICS codes are often used along with economic data to analyze an industry or sector. When a new business is created, they self-select into one or more NAICS codes.
In forestry, there are several designations that represent different areas of the forest products industry. These range from wood products manufacturers, loggers, pulp mills, and forest nurseries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>31 R packages for forest analysts</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/31-r-packages-for-forest-analysts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/31-r-packages-for-forest-analysts/</guid>
      <description>The R program is one of the most popular programs being used by forest analysts today. The power of R comes from its diversity of packages. A package is a collection of functions and data sets developed by R users.
The value of using R packages is that someone else might have already written a suite of functions for you. These can include your coworkers, colleagues, and other professionals. R packages are written to be collaborative so that they can be shared with others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forget spreading and gathering your R data, try pivoting instead</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/forget-spreading-and-gathering-your-r-data-try-pivoting-instead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/forget-spreading-and-gathering-your-r-data-try-pivoting-instead/</guid>
      <description>Reshaping data from a wide to a long format, or vice versa, is one of the most common data manipulation tasks that analysts need to do. One of my first posts on this blog was on how to do this in R.
That post highlighted the spread() and gather() functions available from the tidyr package. As it turns out, the gather() and spread() functions are still available to use but are no longer under active development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wages for logging truckers much lower than other transportation industries</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/wages-for-logging-truckers-much-lower-than-other-transportation-industries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/wages-for-logging-truckers-much-lower-than-other-transportation-industries/</guid>
      <description>“To solve any problem in forestry, first figure out where the roads will go.”
That is a quote that I’ve heard a retired university professor tell students a number of times. There is a lot of wisdom in it: many forest resources are located in remote areas. Hauling products from the woods to the mill can be challenging. The economics of utilizing wood become less appealing if forest products are located far away from the mill that processes it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using clustering with logging industry data</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/using-clustering-with-logging-industry-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/using-clustering-with-logging-industry-data/</guid>
      <description>A forest products company may not always require a precise numeric answer to solve a problem. Oftentimes, understanding a pattern and how data are clustered can suffice.
The benefit of using pattern recognition techniques is that data need not be labeled prior to analyzing them. In contrast to statistical techniques like regression and classification, identifying patterns can unearth new trends in how data are arranged in your organization.
Clustering is an unsupervised ML algorithm that groups items.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do loggers feel? Sentiment analysis on the opinions of logging contractors</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/how-do-loggers-feel-sentiment-analysis-on-the-opinions-of-logging-contractors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/how-do-loggers-feel-sentiment-analysis-on-the-opinions-of-logging-contractors/</guid>
      <description>After we conduct a survey, we have a routine for analyzing the data. Summarize the numerical responses and report values like means for specific questions. Group the data into different demographics and report the means within these categories.
If we ask for any qualitative data through comments (e.g., “What is your opinion of X?”), the responses are always worth reading. We often get a lot of insight from reading an individual’s comments, and these comments can unveil new dimensions of our analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
