<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>science on </title>
    <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/tags/science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in science on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arbor-analytics.com/tags/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Peer review: Lessons learned from reviewing 100 forest science manuscripts</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-07-19-peer-review-lessons-learned-from-reviewing-100-forest-science-manuscripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-07-19-peer-review-lessons-learned-from-reviewing-100-forest-science-manuscripts/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Annie Spratt on Unsplash.
This summer I completed my 100th peer review of a manuscript in forest science. Peer review is mostly a non-compensated service to the profession, but the process probably works as best as any other system for evaluating the merit and impact of scientific studies. The individuals best qualified to evaluate scientific work are scientists working on similar research problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trends in forest carbon papers in the last 20 years</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/trends-in-forest-carbon-literature/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/trends-in-forest-carbon-literature/</guid>
      <description>The number of peer-reviewed research publications on forest carbon has exploded in recent decades. From the signings of the Kyoto Protocol in 1997 to the Paris Agreement in 2015, much of the science and research conducted has been in response to the global challenges and opportunities that forests provide by sequestering and storing carbon.
Forest carbon has also been increasingly studied in forest management and silvicultural practices. New technologies and remote sensing have also brought about new ways to inventory forests for the biomass and carbon they store.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The decline of researchers in forest science</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/the-decline-of-researchers-in-forest-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/the-decline-of-researchers-in-forest-science/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago during a coffee break in a day-long meeting, I was asked by a forester that works for a state agency to connect him with some contacts. He was interested in anyone that works in the forest industry in Minnesota that “does research”.
I work as a faculty member and Extension forester at a Society of American Foresters-accredited institution. I am generally knowledgeable about current forestry research and the people doing it in our state.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
