<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PPP Loans on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/tags/ppp-loans/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PPP Loans on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/tags/ppp-loans/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pandemic assistance to the forest industry: a summary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/events/2022-09-27-pandemic-assistance-to-the-forest-industry-a-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/events/2022-09-27-pandemic-assistance-to-the-forest-industry-a-summary/</guid>
      <description>Forest products and timber harvesting and hauling businesses secured nearly $5 billion of federal funds through the Paycheck Protection Program and Pandemic Assistance to Timber Harvesters and Haulers programs to combat economic challenges presented by the COVID-19 pandemic. These slides were presented at the 2022 Society of American Foresters Convention in Baltimore, MD.&#xA;READ THE SLIDES.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the logging industry in the Lake States used PPP loans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-03-22-how-the-logging-industry-in-the-lake-states-used-ppp-loans/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-03-22-how-the-logging-industry-in-the-lake-states-used-ppp-loans/</guid>
      <description>Logging companies in the US Lake States requested $49.7 million in Paycheck Protection Program loans offered through the Small Business Administration in 2020 and 2021. These loans were offered to 1,445 logging businesses in the Lake States.&#xA;The SBA Paycheck Protection Program provides information on PPP loan distributions to businesses throughout the COVID-19 pandemic. Depending on the size of the business and its needs, loan amounts varied.&#xA;For all logging businesses, the average loan amount was $34,412 and there were an average of 3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the forest products industry used Paycheck Protection Program loans (2022 update)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-02-12-how-the-forest-products-industry-used-paycheck-protection-program-loans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-02-12-how-the-forest-products-industry-used-paycheck-protection-program-loans/</guid>
      <description>Summary&#xD;The Paycheck Protection Program (PPP) offered loans to businesses to provide a direct incentive for them to keep their workers on payroll. Forest products companies across the US received $4.7 billion in PPP loans offered through the Small Business Administration. Over 35,000 loans were offered to forest products companies in the US from April 2020 through May 2021, affecting 487,000 workers in the forest industry.&#xA;The Paycheck Protection Program&#xD;The US Small Business Administration (SBA) managed the Paycheck Protection Program (PPP) between April 2020 and May 2021.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The forest products industry’s use of Paycheck Protection Program loans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-05-23-the-forest-products-industry-s-use-of-paycheck-protection-program-loans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-05-23-the-forest-products-industry-s-use-of-paycheck-protection-program-loans/</guid>
      <description>Summary&#xD;The Paycheck Protection Program (PPP) offered loans to businesses to provide a direct incentive for them to keep their workers on payroll. Forest products companies across the US received $4.7 billion in PPP loans offered through the Small Business Administration. Over 34,000 loans were offered to forest products companies in the US from April 2020 through May 2021, affecting 485,000 workers in the forest industry.&#xA;The Paycheck Protection Program&#xD;The US Small Business Administration (SBA) managed the Paycheck Protection Program (PPP) between April 2020 and May 2021.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the forest products industry using NAICS codes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-05-08-understanding-the-forest-products-industry-using-naics-codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-05-08-understanding-the-forest-products-industry-using-naics-codes/</guid>
      <description>To understand any industry, an analyst should be well acquainted with the codes designating the North American Industry Classification Systems. These NAICS codes are often used along with economic data to analyze an industry or sector. When a new business is created, they self-select into one or more NAICS codes.&#xA;In forestry, there are several designations that represent different areas of the forest products industry. These range from wood products manufacturers, loggers, pulp mills, and forest nurseries.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maine logging industry&#39;s use of PPP loans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-01-23-maine-logging-industry-s-use-of-ppp-loans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-01-23-maine-logging-industry-s-use-of-ppp-loans/</guid>
      <description>Logging companies in Maine requested at least $13.8 million in Paycheck Protection Program loans offered through the Small Business Administration in 2020. These loans were offered to 256 logging businesses in Maine in the spring and early summer of 2020.&#xA;The SBA Paycheck Protection Program Loan Level Data provides information on PPP loan distributions to businesses made through August 8, 2020. Depending on the size of the business and its needs, loan amounts varied.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
