<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning on </title>
    <link>/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine Learning on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to determine accuracy of classification models (with forestry data)</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-determine-accuracy-of-classification-models-with-forestry-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-to-determine-accuracy-of-classification-models-with-forestry-data/</guid>
      <description>Classification is the process when you predict something, and that something is a class or label. It’s widely used when analyzing and modeling forestry data. Data scientists use if often as one of the many machine learning algorithms.
You might have learned about classification in the context of logistic regression. In logistic regression, your outcome is a binary class of data. For example, a tree can be alive or dead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New logging companies with old equipment: Finding patterns in logging businesses using clustering</title>
      <link>/post/new-logging-companies-with-old-equipment-finding-patterns-in-logging-businesses-using-clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/new-logging-companies-with-old-equipment-finding-patterns-in-logging-businesses-using-clustering/</guid>
      <description>Loggers are the backbone of the forest products industry and contribute to the 2.5 million jobs in the US that forests provide. Despite their importance to the industry, many studies have highlighted the challenges that loggers face with regard to economic markets, changing demographics, and an unhealthy outlook on the profession.
As an example in Minnesota, a recent study indicated that the average age of logging businesses continues to grow older, with a third of loggers more than 60 years old.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>