<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Carbon on </title>
    <link>/tags/carbon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Carbon on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/carbon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to calculate carbon from board feet and cords</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-calculate-carbon-from-board-feet-and-cords/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-to-calculate-carbon-from-board-feet-and-cords/</guid>
      <description>Foresters and wood buyers are increasingly being asked about the amount of carbon that trees and forests store. However, foresters and wood buyers do not inventory or buy their wood on a carbon basis. Instead, forests in many regions of the US are inventoried and sold using volume measurements such as board feet and cords. If a forest resources professional knows how measurements like wood volume relate to carbon, he or she can feel empowered when discussing the importance of forests and forest management in the context of carbon with landowners and decision makers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forest carbon cheat sheet</title>
      <link>/post/forest-carbon-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/forest-carbon-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>The Forest Carbon Cheat Sheet is a quick reference guide for converting forest carbon measurements and understanding typical carbon values at the tree, stand, and landscape levels.
The Cheast Sheet is updated with the most recent values published in the US Environmental Protection Agency Inventory of U.S. Greenhouse Gas Emissions and Sinks: 1990-2018.
DOWNLOAD (PDF)
DOWNLOAD (JPEG)
The Forest Carbon Cheat Sheet.
If you have questions or comments on the Cheat Sheet, email Matt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Units in forest carbon numbers: a primer</title>
      <link>/post/units-in-forest-carbon-numbers-a-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/units-in-forest-carbon-numbers-a-primer/</guid>
      <description>Forest analysts are increasingly being asked about the amount of carbon that trees and forests store. However, most analysts are trained in summarizing forestry data sets to obtain measurements such as volume and basal area.
If a forest analyst knows how to “speak carbon”, this can leave them feeling empowered when discussing the importance of forests and forest management in the context of carbon. This can leave a solid impression with landowners and decision makers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much carbon is stored in one trillion trees?</title>
      <link>/post/how-much-carbon-is-stored-in-a-trillion-trees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-much-carbon-is-stored-in-a-trillion-trees/</guid>
      <description>The short answer: About 5.7 times as much than is currently stored in forests in the lower 48 US states and Alaska. One trillion trees equates to about 101 billion metric tons of carbon stored.The Trillion Trees Campaign has been widespread in the news recently. The United States has committed to the initiative, announced at the World Economic Forum in January 2020 and mentioned during President Trump’s annual State of the Union address on 4 February 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to calculate how much carbon is in a tree</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-calculate-how-much-carbon-is-in-a-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-to-calculate-how-much-carbon-is-in-a-tree/</guid>
      <description>Carbon is perhaps the most important attribute in trees today. Forests in the United States sequester about 11% of the total CO2 emissions every year, making them an important tool to combat future global changes. Having accurate models that represent how much carbon is stored in trees is essential for understanding their carbon sequestration potential and are widely used in forest carbon accounting tools.
Most equations that predict the amount carbon in a tree start with first predicting its biomass.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>