<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Forestry on </title>
    <link>/categories/forestry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Forestry on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/forestry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to calculate carbon from board feet and cords</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-calculate-carbon-from-board-feet-and-cords/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-to-calculate-carbon-from-board-feet-and-cords/</guid>
      <description>Foresters and wood buyers are increasingly being asked about the amount of carbon that trees and forests store. However, foresters and wood buyers do not inventory or buy their wood on a carbon basis. Instead, forests in many regions of the US are inventoried and sold using volume measurements such as board feet and cords. If a forest resources professional knows how measurements like wood volume relate to carbon, he or she can feel empowered when discussing the importance of forests and forest management in the context of carbon with landowners and decision makers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disentagling the interactions between site index and disturbance</title>
      <link>/post/disentagling-the-interactions-between-site-index-and-disturbance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/disentagling-the-interactions-between-site-index-and-disturbance/</guid>
      <description>The Black Hills National Forest has been in the news recently after completing a timber sustainability report. In recent years, the Black Hills was one of the US Forest Service’s greatest timber-producing National Forests in the country.
Much of the increase in timber harvest in recent years at the Black Hills National Forest was in response to a deadly mountain pine beetle epidemic. As a result, the new report suggests that current timber harvests are not sustainable into the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The decline of researchers in forest science</title>
      <link>/post/the-decline-of-researchers-in-forest-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-decline-of-researchers-in-forest-science/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago during a coffee break in a day-long meeting, I was asked by a forester that works for a state agency to connect him with some contacts. He was interested in anyone that works in the forest industry in Minnesota that “does research”.
I work as a faculty member and Extension forester at a Society of American Foresters-accredited institution. I am generally knowledgeable about current forestry research and the people doing it in our state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>H-2B guest workers in forestry: by the numbers</title>
      <link>/post/h-2b-forestry-and-conservation-workers-by-the-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/h-2b-forestry-and-conservation-workers-by-the-numbers/</guid>
      <description>Guest workers regenerating a northern Minnesota forest. (photo: @Chris_KTDunham, Twitter)
Guest workers hired through the H-2B visa program get jobs done. This is especially true across many forestry companies. Guest workers plant trees, conduct silvicultural treatments, and assist in tree nursery production.
A strong guest worker program can lead to a future forest products industry that is healthy and sustainable in the long term.
Last week, the Trump administration announced 35,000 additional seasonal H-2B guest worker visas available in 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>