<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Analytics on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/tags/analytics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Analytics on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/tags/analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Preliminary thoughts on using the new National Scale Volume and Biomass Estimators</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2024-02-26-preliminary-thoughts-on-using-the-new-national-scale-volume-and-biomass-estimators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2024-02-26-preliminary-thoughts-on-using-the-new-national-scale-volume-and-biomass-estimators/</guid>
      <description>Last fall the USDA Forest Service released the National Scale Volume Biomass (NSVB), a new modeling system for estimating volume, biomass, and carbon stored in individual trees. These new equations replace the previously-used Component Ratio Method (CRM) and are the result of several years of research. Volume, biomass, and carbon attributes in the US Forest Inventory and Analysis (FIA) database have been updated with values from the new equations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A list of R packages for forestry applications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-11-24-a-list-of-r-packages-for-forestry-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-11-24-a-list-of-r-packages-for-forestry-applications/</guid>
      <description>Image created with DALL·E 3.&#xD;Two years ago I wrote about the different R packages that are available to use in forestry applications. Back then, there were 16,166 packages archived on the Comprehensive R Archive Network (CRAN). Today, the CRAN repository contains 20,102 packages.&#xA;The power of R comes from its diversity of packages. A package is a collection of functions and data sets developed by R users. The value of using R packages is that someone else might have already written a suite of functions for you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How much does adding previous diameter and height growth change FVS predictions?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-10-31-calibrating-fvs-how-much-does-adding-previous-diameter-and-height-growth-change-predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-10-31-calibrating-fvs-how-much-does-adding-previous-diameter-and-height-growth-change-predictions/</guid>
      <description>A brook in western Maine, USA.&#xD;There’s a recent paper by Claudia Herbert and others that’s come up in several meetings I’ve been in the last several months. The paper describes an analysis they used with forecasting forest carbon in California using the Forest Vegetation Simulator. They concluded that using FVS “out-of-the-box”, i.e., with no local calibrations of modifications, “overpredicts carbon sequestration in live trees that remain alive ten years later by 27%, on average.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using R and Python to get forest resource data through the EVALIDator API</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-10-25-using-r-and-python-to-get-forest-resource-data-through-the-evalidator-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-10-25-using-r-and-python-to-get-forest-resource-data-through-the-evalidator-api/</guid>
      <description>If you work with forestry data across the United States, you’ve probably had to turn to Forest Inventory and Analysis (FIA) data at one time or another to look at the status and trends in our forest resources. The FIA database has information contained from over 130,000 forest inventory plots across the country.&#xA;One of the tools that analysts often use to access FIA data is the the EVALIDator web interface.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent updates to tidyverse functions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-09-13-recent-changes-in-the-tidyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-09-13-recent-changes-in-the-tidyverse/</guid>
      <description>I recently watched the video “Teaching the tidyverse in 2023” by Mine Çetinkaya-Rundel to learn more about recent changes to my favorite R package. I learned quite a bit of new tricks and techniques for my everyday R coding and sharing a few of them here.&#xA;I’ll use the elm data set from the stats4nr package as I work through a few examples in the post. This data set contains observations on 333 cedar elm trees (Ulmus crassifolia Nutt.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementing climate adaptive silviculture scenarios in the Forest Vegetation Simulator</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-08-22-implementing-adaptive-silviculture-scenarios-in-the-forest-vegetation-simulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-08-22-implementing-adaptive-silviculture-scenarios-in-the-forest-vegetation-simulator/</guid>
      <description>The Adaptive Silvicultre for Climate Change Project at the Chippewa National Forest, Minnesota, USA. Photo: Josh Kragthorpe.&#xD;If you follow the latest research in forestry, it’s hard not to come across studies relating to adaptive silviculture. In a nutshell, adaptive silviculture is “designed to specifically address climate change impacts and vulnerabilities to meet management goals and objectives.”&#xA;If you’ve ever been on a field tour of a forest that has recently seen a timber harvest and has undergone an adaptive silviculture treatment, you were likely impressed with the complex spatial distribution of residual trees following the harvest.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linear quantile mixed models: applications in forestry</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-07-31-linear-quantile-mixed-models-applications-in-forestry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-07-31-linear-quantile-mixed-models-applications-in-forestry/</guid>
      <description>Example output comparing predictions from three models fit with linear quantile mixed models and one fit using ordinary least squares.&#xD;Mixed models have been used for decades by forest biometricians and statisticians. They have become popular because forestry and natural resources data are often nested, allowing the analyst to account for spatial and temporal correlation among measurements. Forest plots are often measured within stands, stands are located within ownerships, and a collection of ownerships comprise a landscape.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making R graphs more accessible using BrailleR</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-06-30-making-r-graphs-more-accessible-using-brailler/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-06-30-making-r-graphs-more-accessible-using-brailler/</guid>
      <description>An example use of alt text for a scatterplot made in R, with description of the scatterplot provided by the BrailleR package below the graph.&#xD;You might have seen these prompts while you’re uploading an image to social media or anywhere else on the internet: “Add alt text here.” Alt text describes what’s contained in an image or figure on a webpage. It’s useful because it can be used by screen readers for visually impaired people.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying the shade tolerance of climate-adapted tree species in the Northeast</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-05-25-quantifying-the-shade-tolerance-of-climate-adapted-tree-species-in-the-northeast/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-05-25-quantifying-the-shade-tolerance-of-climate-adapted-tree-species-in-the-northeast/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I attended Dr. Tony D’Amato’s excellent webinar “Looking at Forest Carbon from Multiple Dimensions”. The content of the webinar was excellent and I encourage anyone involved with forest management and forest carbon to view it.&#xA;One primary concept from the webinar stood out to me: many of the future tree species that are anticipated to be well adapted to future conditions are less shade tolerant that current trees on the landscape.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sampling design and statistical approaches in forestry</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/events/2023-05-22-sampling-design-and-statistical-approaches-in-forestry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/events/2023-05-22-sampling-design-and-statistical-approaches-in-forestry/</guid>
      <description>&#xD;This workshop for Tag Ng showcased how sampling and statistics can be used in forestry applications. The two-hour virtual workshop discussed common sampling design used in forestry and statistical approaches with forest inventory data. Example coding sessions used the forestsamplr and tidymodels packages in R.&#xA;VIEW SLIDES&#xD;VIEW R CODE AND DATA&#xD;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bootstrapped resampling to model tree biomass</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-04-12-bootstrapped-resampling-estimates-to-predict-tree-height/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-04-12-bootstrapped-resampling-estimates-to-predict-tree-height/</guid>
      <description>In one of the first presentations I gave as a graduate student, I discussed a set of regression equations that fit a nonlinear model predicting a forest growth index for several species. As all graduate students do, I spent considerable time preparing my slides and practicing my talk. The presentation went well.&#xA;I used a data splitting approach in my analysis that I presented on, a common technique that trains a model on a large portion of the data (usually around 70%) then tests it on a smaller portion of data not used in model fitting (usually around 30%).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying harvested wood products and forest management in carbon analyses</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/events/2023-03-19-quantifying-harvested-wood-products-and-forest-management-in-carbon-analyses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/events/2023-03-19-quantifying-harvested-wood-products-and-forest-management-in-carbon-analyses/</guid>
      <description>There remains great interest in understanding the role of forest management in storing and sequestering carbon. While researchers and land managers have a number of tools available to quantify the impacts of forest management on carbon stocks in growing forests, fewer tools are available that depict the carbon stored “off site” in the form of harvested wood products. These can include short-lived products (i.e., paper or pulp) or long-lived ones (i.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Imputing missing tree heights from a forest inventory</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-02-15-imputing-missing-tree-heights-from-a-forest-inventory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-02-15-imputing-missing-tree-heights-from-a-forest-inventory/</guid>
      <description>Eastern white pine trees at sunrise in Maine.&#xD;Total height is one of the most useful measurements of a tree, but it’s often not measured. This is because measuring heights takes considerable time and effort. While it may be easy for a forester to measure the diameter of a tree, to obtain a proper measurement of a tree you generally need to walk away from it. This can take a lot of time if there are dozens of trees on a forest inventory plot.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calculating carbon in standing dead trees</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-02-09-calculating-carbon-in-standing-dead-trees/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-02-09-calculating-carbon-in-standing-dead-trees/</guid>
      <description>A standing dead balsam fir tree in Maine.&#xD;Quantifying the presence and abundance of standing dead trees (SDTs) is notoriously difficult. While live and healthy trees generally appear similar in form and appearance to other live and healthy trees, no two standing dead trees are alike.&#xA;Trees that recently died within a few months can have most of their tops and limbs intact. Their foliage may even still be attached.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Timberlands as investments continue to rise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-01-27-timberlands-as-an-investment-continue-to-rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-01-27-timberlands-as-an-investment-continue-to-rise/</guid>
      <description>Forests and timberlands have long been popular investments that provide returns comparable to other economy-wide measures. The changing private ownership patterns in US forests over the last several decades, as timberlands have been owned or managed by timber investment management organizations or real estate investment trusts, has led to a rise in the benefits of timberland as an investment.&#xA;The National Council of Real Estate Investment Fiduciaries (NCREIF) recently posted fourth quarter and annual returns for their Timberland Index, an index representing 464 investment-grade timberland properties with a market value of $24.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forest carbon cheat sheet: updated for 2022</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-12-21-forest-carbon-cheat-sheet-updated-for-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-12-21-forest-carbon-cheat-sheet-updated-for-2022/</guid>
      <description>The Forest Carbon Cheat Sheet is a quick reference guide for converting forest carbon measurements and understanding typical carbon values at the tree, stand, and landscape levels.&#xA;The Cheat Sheet has been updated with the most recent values published in the US Environmental Protection Agency Inventory of U.S. Greenhouse Gas Emissions and Sinks: 1990-2020.&#xA;DOWNLOAD (PDF)&#xA;DOWNLOAD (PNG)&#xA;The Forest Carbon Cheat Sheet.&#xA;–&#xA;By Matt Russell. Email Matt with any questions or comments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doing statistics in the tidyverse: exploring the infer package</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-12-14-doing-statistics-in-the-tidyverse-exploring-the-infer-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-12-14-doing-statistics-in-the-tidyverse-exploring-the-infer-package/</guid>
      <description>If you use R software for your data analysis, you are likely familiar with the tidyverse. The tidyverse package is a “megapackage” in R that includes several packages that import, reshape, and visualize data in a consistent manner, among other tasks.&#xA;Like many analysts, I use the tidyverse suite of functions often for importing, wrangling, and visualizing data. More and more I’m using the tidymodels package to apply statistical modeling techniques like regression and random forests on data I work with.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent research insights in forest biomass and carbon estimation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/events/2022-12-01-recent-research-insights-in-forest-biomass-and-carbon-estimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/events/2022-12-01-recent-research-insights-in-forest-biomass-and-carbon-estimation/</guid>
      <description>Recent research within the forest biometrics community is helping to generate more precise estimates of forest carbon using new methods and technologies. This presentation was delivered to the California Air Resources Board Public Workshop on US Forest Projects Compliance Offset Protocol on November 30, 2022.&#xA;READ THE SLIDES.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New updates for tools that query Forest Inventory and Analysis data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-11-23-new-updates-for-tools-that-query-forest-inventory-and-analysis-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-11-23-new-updates-for-tools-that-query-forest-inventory-and-analysis-data/</guid>
      <description>The US national forest inventory has information contained from over 130,000 forest inventory plots across the country. Data collected and maintained by the Forest Inventory and Analysis (FIA) program are needed for answering core forestry questions, and having the right tools to help extract specific data that fits the analysis is essential.&#xA;After attending the FIA Science Stakeholder Meeting last week, I was happy to learn about some important updates to two tools that are widely used by forest analysts: the FIA EVALIDator program and the FIA DataMart.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How many homes heat with wood?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-11-09-home-heating-with-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-11-09-home-heating-with-wood/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Andreas Pajuvirta on Unsplash&#xD;The bill that was left on our door was what many homeowners are hit with this time of year: $1,082 for 175 gallons.&#xA;Like most homes in central Maine, we heat with fuel oil in the winter. It’s a common source of home heating across northern New England, and the high price of heating oil was brought up repeatedly throughout the midterm elections.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to spot poor data analyses</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-10-20-how-to-spot-poor-data-analyses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-10-20-how-to-spot-poor-data-analyses/</guid>
      <description>Being an excellent data analyst requires you to understand the techniques that go into analyzing data and how to communicate them effectively. While having a foundation in statistics and the quantitative sciences is essential, the most effective data analysts communicate information that influences decision makers.&#xA;Unfortunately, there are plenty of examples of sloppy data analyses that distort the reality of what data can tell us. As an example, genetics researchers have found that Microsoft Excel’s autocorrecting feature had led to errors in 30% of gene list observations over a six year span.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>P-ing in the woods: p-values in forest science</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-10-10-p-ing-in-the-woods-p-values-in-forest-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-10-10-p-ing-in-the-woods-p-values-in-forest-science/</guid>
      <description>A meme about p-values. Hat tip to Matt Dancho for the idea for the graphic.&#xD;The statistics community has had a lot of discussion in recent years about the role of p-values and statistical significance. This has led some to question if we’re relying too much on them as a way of interpreting results from a statistical analysis.&#xA;The “p” in p-value stands for probability, or the probability under a statistical model that a summary of the data would be equal to or more extreme than its observed value.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A review of the log trucking workforce and comparisons to other industries</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/events/2022-09-27-a-review-of-the-log-trucking-workforce-and-comparisons-to-other-industries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/events/2022-09-27-a-review-of-the-log-trucking-workforce-and-comparisons-to-other-industries/</guid>
      <description>The trucking industry is faced with a number of challenges, including recruiting workers, pending retirements, and an increase in demand due to e-commerce sales. These slides provide an overview of the log trucking workforce and were presented at the Forest Resources Association’s Fall Board Meeting in Portland, ME.&#xA;READ THE SLIDES.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FVS and CBM-CFS3: Comparing two forest simulation models </title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-08-04-fvs-and-cbm-cfs3-comparing-two-forest-carbon-accounting-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-08-04-fvs-and-cbm-cfs3-comparing-two-forest-carbon-accounting-tools/</guid>
      <description>Analysts in the forestry community often turn to models to simulate what a forest will look like in the future. Whether it’s simulating a forest management treatment or forecasting the effects of a natural disturbance, models are required tools for understanding how forests will grow.&#xA;Increasingly, models are being used to understand forest carbon stocks and stock changes. As we strive to quantify the role of forests in offsetting carbon dioxide emissions, having reliable tools to understand forest dynamics is essential.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simple volume to weight conversion for US tree species</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-07-27-simple-volume-to-weight-conversion-for-us-tree-species/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-07-27-simple-volume-to-weight-conversion-for-us-tree-species/</guid>
      <description>Foresters are accustomed to converting units of measure from one to another. Data are often collected in one unit of measure (e.g., the height of a tree in feet), but need to be converted to another for some part of the analysis or report (e.g., its height in meters).&#xA;When it comes to calculating the volume of a tree, the number of equations and models are overwhelming. Not only are there a myriad of log rules to determine wood volume of standing timber, but even more volume equations can make determining wood volume for a species of interest a mess.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New book: Statistics in Natural Resources: Applications with R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-07-20-new-book-statistics-in-natural-resources-applications-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-07-20-new-book-statistics-in-natural-resources-applications-with-r/</guid>
      <description>At the start of the pandemic in 2020, I was worried. Not just for the serious global health impacts, but also for the workload I would soon be faced with.&#xA;I taught an introductory statistics course for graduate students in the natural resources and agricultural disciplines, and was scrambling to find out how I would migrate my course material to an online, asynchronous format.&#xA;At the same time, I was searching for a different textbook to use for the course.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How &#34;big&#34; are the Big Tree Champions?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-05-23-how-big-are-the-big-tree-champions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-05-23-how-big-are-the-big-tree-champions/</guid>
      <description>You might have heard this before: “I just saw the largest X tree in the state!”&#xA;I have always been curious about the trees that make the list of state tree champions, or “big trees”. For nearly every state in the US, a list of the largest trees of each species are maintained. As landowners and foresters roam the woods, they can report a potential champion tree. (For context, in 2018 a team of wildlife researchers came across the largest jack pine in the US when they were studying wolves in northern Minnesota.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading in data quickly into R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-05-19-reading-in-data-quickly-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-05-19-reading-in-data-quickly-in-r/</guid>
      <description>If you’re like me, you work with a lot of data files in your daily analytical work. Despite the increase in cloud computing, reading in files locally to the machine your working on is common.&#xA;You want a rapid summary of your data and don’t want to wait forever for your computer to read in the file you’re working with. To do this, you want to use functions that are efficient and effective for working with large amounts of data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harvested wood products in the Forest Vegetation Simulator</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-04-23-harvested-wood-products-in-the-forest-vegetation-simulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-04-23-harvested-wood-products-in-the-forest-vegetation-simulator/</guid>
      <description>Carbon is stored and sequestered in growing forests. It can also can be stored “off site” in the form of harvested wood products. These can be in short-lived products (i.e., paper or pulp) or long-lived ones (i.e., utility poles).&#xA;Harvested wood products in use and solid waste disposal sites (e.g., landfills) represent 4.5% of the total amount of carbon in the US. When using wood products, lower emissions are used compared fossil fuel-intensive materials such as steel and concrete.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the logging industry in the Lake States used PPP loans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-03-22-how-the-logging-industry-in-the-lake-states-used-ppp-loans/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-03-22-how-the-logging-industry-in-the-lake-states-used-ppp-loans/</guid>
      <description>Logging companies in the US Lake States requested $49.7 million in Paycheck Protection Program loans offered through the Small Business Administration in 2020 and 2021. These loans were offered to 1,445 logging businesses in the Lake States.&#xA;The SBA Paycheck Protection Program provides information on PPP loan distributions to businesses throughout the COVID-19 pandemic. Depending on the size of the business and its needs, loan amounts varied.&#xA;For all logging businesses, the average loan amount was $34,412 and there were an average of 3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the forest products industry used Paycheck Protection Program loans (2022 update)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-02-12-how-the-forest-products-industry-used-paycheck-protection-program-loans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-02-12-how-the-forest-products-industry-used-paycheck-protection-program-loans/</guid>
      <description>Summary&#xD;The Paycheck Protection Program (PPP) offered loans to businesses to provide a direct incentive for them to keep their workers on payroll. Forest products companies across the US received $4.7 billion in PPP loans offered through the Small Business Administration. Over 35,000 loans were offered to forest products companies in the US from April 2020 through May 2021, affecting 487,000 workers in the forest industry.&#xA;The Paycheck Protection Program&#xD;The US Small Business Administration (SBA) managed the Paycheck Protection Program (PPP) between April 2020 and May 2021.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Timberlands as investments see biggest gain since 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-01-22-visualizing-timberland-returns-in-the-last-10-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-01-22-visualizing-timberland-returns-in-the-last-10-years/</guid>
      <description>Forests and timberlands have long been popular investments that provide returns comparable to other economy-wide measures. The changing private ownership patterns in US forests over the last several decades, as timberlands have been owned or managed by timber investment management organizations or real estate investment trusts, has led to a rise in the benefits of timberland as an investment.&#xA;The National Council of Real Estate Investment Fiduciaries (NCREIF) recently posted fourth-quarter returns for their Timberland Index, an index representing 454 investment-grade timberland properties with a market value of $24 billion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five R packages every forest analyst should be using</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-01-14-six-r-packages-every-forest-analysts-should-be-using/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-01-14-six-r-packages-every-forest-analysts-should-be-using/</guid>
      <description>The R program is one of the most popular programs being used by forest analysts today. Forest analysts use R packages, or collections of functions and data sets, to help guide their everyday work.&#xA;Last year I wrote about 31 R packages available to forest analysts available on the Comprehensive R Archive Network (CRAN) package repository. For perspective, as of today CRAN has archived 18,732 packages since 2006.&#xA;R users also make packages available on GitHub, particularly for specific disciplines like forest inventory and measurements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What statistics students in natural resources want to learn more about</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-12-22-what-statistics-students-want-to-learn-more-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-12-22-what-statistics-students-want-to-learn-more-about/</guid>
      <description>As the holidays approach, it’s always a great time of year to reflect back and look forward. This post will describe my approach to this as it relates to a class that just wrapped up for the Fall 2021 semester.&#xA;I instruct the course NR 5021: Statistics for Agricultural and Natural Resources Professionals at the University of Minnesota. The class has between 25 and 40 graduate students enrolled in a given year, a mix between students studying natural resources, agriculture, and plant sciences.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing forest carbon trends in the last thirty years</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-11-15-visualizing-forest-carbon-tredns-in-the-last-30-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-11-15-visualizing-forest-carbon-tredns-in-the-last-30-years/</guid>
      <description>Trees and forests sequester carbon dioxide and other greenhouse gases from the atmosphere. This makes them a natural climate solution. This also encourages managers to quantify carbon attributes along with the myriad of other benefits that forests provide.&#xA;The value of carbon in forests has seen a tremendous increase in recent years. The increased role of forests in meeting climate challenges has required analysts to have a better understanding of carbon attributes in the forests they work in.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Random forests: a tutorial with forestry data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-09-26-random-forests-a-tutorial-with-forestry-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-09-26-random-forests-a-tutorial-with-forestry-data/</guid>
      <description>Random forests have quickly become one of the most popular analytical techniques used in forestry today. Random forests (RF) are a machine learning technique that differ in many ways to traditional prediction models such as regression. Random forests can handle a lot of data, can be applied to classification or regression problems, and rank the relative importance of many variables that are related to a response variable of interest.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The importance of citizen data scientists in forest analytics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-09-07-the-importance-of-citizen-data-scientists-in-forest-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-09-07-the-importance-of-citizen-data-scientists-in-forest-analytics/</guid>
      <description>As a part of my work with the University of Minnesota Extension, we run the Assessing Vegetation Impacts from Deer program. The AVID program engages citizen scientists to monitor tree seedlings that are susceptible to browse from white-tailed deer. With little information on deer browse impacts for most of Minnesota’s tree species, the data are beginning to provide insights on how deer browse degrades the health of the forest.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forest carbon: key definitions and numbers in perspective  </title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-08-08-forest-carbon-key-definitions-and-numbers-in-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-08-08-forest-carbon-key-definitions-and-numbers-in-perspective/</guid>
      <description>Carbon storage in US forests. Source: USDA Forest Service.&#xA;Carbon is quickly becoming one of the hottest forest products of the 2020s. The term “carbon” is a broad one, and when reading an article or listening to a speaker, you may not know exactly which process or specific term is being referred to.&#xA;Here are a few basic terms that will help guide your understanding:&#xA;A carbon pool is a component of the forest that can gain or lose carbon over time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drought in the US West: impacts from the last ten years</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-07-23-drought-in-the-us-west-impacts-in-the-last-10-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-07-23-drought-in-the-us-west-impacts-in-the-last-10-years/</guid>
      <description>Drought conditions in the western US, 20 July 2021. From US Drought Monitor.&#xA;Much of the western United States is currently under severe drought conditions. Drought impacts trees and forests in the short and long term. Trees and forests can tolerate some extended dry periods depending of species and local conditions, but without adequate moisture availability, drought can ultimately lead to tree mortality.&#xA;Perhaps the greatest impact of drought is the stress it places on trees.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testing the assumption: Half of the biomass of a tree is carbon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-06-18-testing-the-assumption-half-of-the-biomass-of-a-tree-is-carbon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-06-18-testing-the-assumption-half-of-the-biomass-of-a-tree-is-carbon/</guid>
      <description>“Half of the biomass of a tree is carbon.” This has been a widely spoken statement made by many foresters and scientists alike. Most forest carbon assessments use the 50% rule and it generally works well.&#xA;In forest analytics, determining the amount of carbon in a tree is first based on estimating its biomass. At the individual tree level, a biomass equation can be developed based on a tree’s diameter, height, species, region, and other tree and stand characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forest carbon cheat sheet: updated for 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-06-12-forest-carbon-cheat-sheet-updated-for-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-06-12-forest-carbon-cheat-sheet-updated-for-2021/</guid>
      <description>The Forest Carbon Cheat Sheet is a quick reference guide for converting forest carbon measurements and understanding typical carbon values at the tree, stand, and landscape levels.&#xA;The Cheat Sheet has been updated with the most recent values published in the US Environmental Protection Agency Inventory of U.S. Greenhouse Gas Emissions and Sinks: 1990-2019.&#xA;DOWNLOAD (PDF)&#xA;DOWNLOAD (JPEG)&#xA;–&#xA;By Matt Russell. Email Matt with any questions or comments. Sign up for my monthly newsletter for in-depth analysis on data and analytics in the forest products industry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How well does the &#34;quick and dirty&#34; standard deviation approximation work?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-06-04-how-well-does-the-quick-and-dirty-standard-deviation-approximation-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-06-04-how-well-does-the-quick-and-dirty-standard-deviation-approximation-work/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Chris Liverani on Unsplash.&#xA;The standard deviation measures the dispersion of individual samples around a mean value. It is one of the most useful measures in forestry and natural resources because it quantifies the “noise” in a sample of data.&#xA;When I was learning statistics in an introductory course, I was shown a formula to approximate the standard deviation. Rather than needing to calculate how far each observation was from the mean value, a key component of the standard deviation calculation, this formula only required knowing the largest and smallest value in the data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The forest products industry’s use of Paycheck Protection Program loans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-05-23-the-forest-products-industry-s-use-of-paycheck-protection-program-loans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-05-23-the-forest-products-industry-s-use-of-paycheck-protection-program-loans/</guid>
      <description>Summary&#xD;The Paycheck Protection Program (PPP) offered loans to businesses to provide a direct incentive for them to keep their workers on payroll. Forest products companies across the US received $4.7 billion in PPP loans offered through the Small Business Administration. Over 34,000 loans were offered to forest products companies in the US from April 2020 through May 2021, affecting 485,000 workers in the forest industry.&#xA;The Paycheck Protection Program&#xD;The US Small Business Administration (SBA) managed the Paycheck Protection Program (PPP) between April 2020 and May 2021.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harvested wood products: a growing contributor to US carbon storage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-05-15-harvested-wood-products-an-increasing-contributor-to-us-carbon-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-05-15-harvested-wood-products-an-increasing-contributor-to-us-carbon-storage/</guid>
      <description>There has been a lot of talk recently about the importance of carbon in forests. Carbon dioxide is the leading source of greenhouse gas emissions, resulting from burning fossil fuels for transportation and energy and producing electricity, among other sources. Trees sequester carbon dioxide from the air and turn it into carbon stored in wood. As a result, healthy trees and forests increase carbon storage and avoid greenhouse gas emissions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating animated bar charts to visualize sawtimber prices</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-04-26-creating-animated-bar-charts-to-visualize-satimber-prices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-04-26-creating-animated-bar-charts-to-visualize-satimber-prices/</guid>
      <description>If you’re on social media, you’ve probably seen animated bar charts. My favorite is one that shows the popularity of data science software through time.&#xA;Animated bar graphs are effective when you have a categorical variable that has a different value at multiple time periods. This is why animated bar graphs work well to visualize time series data. These data might typically be represented by multiple lines on a graph that “cross” over time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Importing FIA data to analyze forest carbon with tidyFIA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-04-03-importing-fia-data-to-analyze-biomass-data-with-tidyfia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-04-03-importing-fia-data-to-analyze-biomass-data-with-tidyfia/</guid>
      <description>I used to cringe every time I needed to import Forest Inventory and Analysis data. The data files that contain tree observations for a single state can exceed 100 megabytes. The file I downloaded six months ago might or might not contain the most recent data for that state.&#xA;There are a few R packages that have been developed in the last several years that help import FIA data. The tidyFIA package is one of them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forest carbon and short-lived trees</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/forest-carbon-markets-and-short-lived-trees/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/forest-carbon-markets-and-short-lived-trees/</guid>
      <description>I spoke with a forest products company representative this week who expressed concern with “extending rotations” so that carbon is locked up in trees for a longer time. Many forest carbon markets are proposing delaying harvesting for a few years so that more carbon accumulates over time.&#xA;The particular concern was in Minnesota where aspen, the state’s most commercially important species, is crucial to the forest products economy. Aspen is a short-lived, shade-intolerant species that is managed using even-aged silvicultural techniques.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coverting forest inventory data from volume to carbon </title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/coverting-wood-scaled-as-weight-to-carbon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/coverting-wood-scaled-as-weight-to-carbon/</guid>
      <description>The amount of carbon in a forest is a key metric that decision-makers want to know. Accurate estimates of forest carbon are needed if a landowner is interested in enrolling a forest into carbon markets.&#xA;Unfortunately, most forest inventories continue to measure the amount of wood in a stand in terms of the volume it contains. Forest analysts also rely on historical forest inventory data to project future forest structure and composition - it is not unlikely to rely on inventory data that are more than 20 years old.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trends in forest carbon papers in the last 20 years</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/trends-in-forest-carbon-literature/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/trends-in-forest-carbon-literature/</guid>
      <description>The number of peer-reviewed research publications on forest carbon has exploded in recent decades. From the signings of the Kyoto Protocol in 1997 to the Paris Agreement in 2015, much of the science and research conducted has been in response to the global challenges and opportunities that forests provide by sequestering and storing carbon.&#xA;Forest carbon has also been increasingly studied in forest management and silvicultural practices. New technologies and remote sensing have also brought about new ways to inventory forests for the biomass and carbon they store.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mixed models in R: a primer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/mixed-models-a-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/mixed-models-a-primer/</guid>
      <description>Myself and a team of coauthors recently submitted a manuscript that analyzed forest composition data from a silvicultural study. Here is a comment from a peer reviewer that reviewed the work:&#xA;“I would like the authors to justify not using mixed models or to change their analyses for mixed models.”&#xA;The comment urged us to reevaluate the analysis of the data. Ultimately we redid the analysis using a mixed model framework, instead of using the traditional analysis of variance approach taught in many introductory statistics classes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ask how you want your data - and be specific</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/ask-how-how-want-your-data-and-be-specific/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/ask-how-how-want-your-data-and-be-specific/</guid>
      <description>I have been analyzing the submissions to the University of Minnesota Extension’s Tree and Woodland Carbon Capture Challenge. The Challenge is an activity that asked Minnesotans to measure trees and woodlands to observe how much carbon they sequester over a year.&#xA;The audience that participated in this activity included homeowners and private woodland owners with a love for trees. In total, 26 people measured an individual tree and typed their measurements into a Google Form answering the question “What is the diameter of your tree, measured in inches?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Random forests in a nutshell</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/random-forests-in-a-nutshell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/random-forests-in-a-nutshell/</guid>
      <description>Random forests have exploded in popularity in the forestry discipline in recent years. Random forests (RF) are a quantitative tool categorized as a machine learning technique. Analysts prefer to use RF methods because they can handle large amounts of data, provide the relative importance of a many variables, and can be applied to classification or regression problems.&#xA;The following graph shows the number of articles from four common journals in the forestry discipline that contained the term “random forests” in the article.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New state-level forest carbon fact sheets available</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/new-state-level-forest-carbon-fact-sheets-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/new-state-level-forest-carbon-fact-sheets-available/</guid>
      <description>An example forest carbon fact sheet from Maine.&#xA;Trees and forests sequester carbon dioxide and other greenhouse gases from the atmosphere. Despite the increasing importance of understanding the amount of carbon that forests can store and sequester, easy-to-access information at the state level is difficult to obtain.&#xA;Arbor Custom Analytics recently worked with the Forest Resources Association to create a series of fact sheets at the state, region, and national level.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>States with the biggest gains in forest carbon over the last 30 years</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/states-with-the-biggest-gains-in-forest-carbon-over-the-last-30-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/states-with-the-biggest-gains-in-forest-carbon-over-the-last-30-years/</guid>
      <description>Trees and forests sequester carbon dioxide and other greenhouse gases from the atmosphere. This makes them a natural climate solution. This also encourages managers to quantify carbon attributes along with the myriad of other benefits that forests provide.&#xA;The value of carbon in forests has seen a tremendous increase in recent years. The increase in voluntary forest carbon markets have required analysts to have a better understanding of carbon attributes in the forests they work in.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31 R packages for forest analysts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/31-r-packages-for-forest-analysts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/31-r-packages-for-forest-analysts/</guid>
      <description>The R program is one of the most popular programs being used by forest analysts today. The power of R comes from its diversity of packages. A package is a collection of functions and data sets developed by R users.&#xA;The value of using R packages is that someone else might have already written a suite of functions for you. These can include your coworkers, colleagues, and other professionals. R packages are written to be collaborative so that they can be shared with others.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forget spreading and gathering your R data, try pivoting instead</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/forget-spreading-and-gathering-your-r-data-try-pivoting-instead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/forget-spreading-and-gathering-your-r-data-try-pivoting-instead/</guid>
      <description>Reshaping data from a wide to a long format, or vice versa, is one of the most common data manipulation tasks that analysts need to do. One of my first posts on this blog was on how to do this in R.&#xA;That post highlighted the spread() and gather() functions available from the tidyr package. As it turns out, the gather() and spread() functions are still available to use but are no longer under active development.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on the American Forestry Conference</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/reflections-on-the-american-forestry-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/reflections-on-the-american-forestry-conference/</guid>
      <description>Shawn Baker presents on trends in logging businesses.&#xA;Last week I tuned into the American Forestry Conference, a virtual conference on the forest products industry and how forestry businesses can reshape the future US economy. The conference, organized by the Georgia Forestry Association, had 35 speakers that discussed topics such as the challenges and opportunities of the role of forestry in the current and future economic climate. In an email, the organizing committee reported 540 attendees from 26 US states.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forest carbon stocks in every US state</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/carbon-by-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/carbon-by-state/</guid>
      <description>photo by Sean MacEntee&#xA;In April 2020, the USDA Forest Service published Greenhouse gas emissions and removals from forest land, woodlands, and urban trees in the United States, 1990-2018. What makes this annual report unique is that forest carbon estimates are reported for each US state. Data are available in an appendix which lists forest carbon stocks and flux for each state from 1990 to 2018.&#xA;Across the US, forests, urban trees, and harvested wood products are the largest carbon sink.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using clustering with logging industry data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/using-clustering-with-logging-industry-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/using-clustering-with-logging-industry-data/</guid>
      <description>A forest products company may not always require a precise numeric answer to solve a problem. Oftentimes, understanding a pattern and how data are clustered can suffice.&#xA;The benefit of using pattern recognition techniques is that data need not be labeled prior to analyzing them. In contrast to statistical techniques like regression and classification, identifying patterns can unearth new trends in how data are arranged in your organization.&#xA;Clustering is an unsupervised ML algorithm that groups items.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polar area diagrams in celebration of Florence Nightingale</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/polar-area-diagrams-in-celebration-of-florence-nightingale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/polar-area-diagrams-in-celebration-of-florence-nightingale/</guid>
      <description>In 1858 the general public was familiar with seeing statistics presented in tables. Visualizations showing statistics and data were not widely used and were difficult to construct. One visualization that was shown to Queen Victoria in this year would live on and continue to be used in the 21st century.&#xA;The visualization showed the number of deaths from soldiers in the Crimean War, fought in the 1850s. Specifically, the visualization showed the number of deaths that occurred from preventable diseases, wounds, and other causes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do loggers feel? Sentiment analysis on the opinions of logging contractors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/how-do-loggers-feel-sentiment-analysis-on-the-opinions-of-logging-contractors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/how-do-loggers-feel-sentiment-analysis-on-the-opinions-of-logging-contractors/</guid>
      <description>After we conduct a survey, we have a routine for analyzing the data. Summarize the numerical responses and report values like means for specific questions. Group the data into different demographics and report the means within these categories.&#xA;If we ask for any qualitative data through comments (e.g., “What is your opinion of X?”), the responses are always worth reading. We often get a lot of insight from reading an individual’s comments, and these comments can unveil new dimensions of our analysis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting your data into R from Google Sheets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/getting-your-data-into-r-from-google-sheets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/getting-your-data-into-r-from-google-sheets/</guid>
      <description>If you’re like me, more of the data you use on a daily basis are stored in Google Sheets. You might be using fewer Excel spreadsheets and .csv files. I recently researched the most up-to-date ways to import data from an Access database into R. (It had been a while since I imported data from a database.)&#xA;Using Google Sheets to store data has several advantages:&#xA;Multiple people can collaborate on the same data set,&#xD;Information entered into a Google Form can populate data in a Google Spreadsheet,&#xD;Data can be accessed and edited both online and offline, and&#xD;Google Sheets can be converted to Excel spreadsheets, and vice versa.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to calculate carbon from board feet and cords</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/how-to-calculate-carbon-from-board-feet-and-cords/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/how-to-calculate-carbon-from-board-feet-and-cords/</guid>
      <description>Foresters and wood buyers are increasingly being asked about the amount of carbon that trees and forests store. However, foresters and wood buyers do not inventory or buy their wood on a carbon basis. Instead, forests in many regions of the US are inventoried and sold using volume measurements such as board feet and cords. If a forest resources professional knows how measurements like wood volume relate to carbon, he or she can feel empowered when discussing the importance of forests and forest management in the context of carbon with landowners and decision makers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disentagling the interactions between site index and disturbance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/disentagling-the-interactions-between-site-index-and-disturbance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/disentagling-the-interactions-between-site-index-and-disturbance/</guid>
      <description>The Black Hills National Forest has been in the news recently after completing a timber sustainability report. In recent years, the Black Hills was one of the US Forest Service’s greatest timber-producing National Forests in the country.&#xA;Much of the increase in timber harvest in recent years at the Black Hills National Forest was in response to a deadly mountain pine beetle epidemic. As a result, the new report suggests that current timber harvests are not sustainable into the future.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forest carbon cheat sheet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/forest-carbon-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/forest-carbon-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>The Forest Carbon Cheat Sheet is a quick reference guide for converting forest carbon measurements and understanding typical carbon values at the tree, stand, and landscape levels.&#xA;The Cheast Sheet is updated with the most recent values published in the US Environmental Protection Agency Inventory of U.S. Greenhouse Gas Emissions and Sinks: 1990-2018.&#xA;DOWNLOAD (PDF)&#xA;DOWNLOAD (JPEG)&#xA;The Forest Carbon Cheat Sheet.&#xA;If you have questions or comments on the Cheat Sheet, email Matt.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Units in forest carbon numbers: a primer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/units-in-forest-carbon-numbers-a-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/units-in-forest-carbon-numbers-a-primer/</guid>
      <description>Forest analysts are increasingly being asked about the amount of carbon that trees and forests store. However, most analysts are trained in summarizing forestry data sets to obtain measurements such as volume and basal area.&#xA;If a forest analyst knows how to “speak carbon”, this can leave them feeling empowered when discussing the importance of forests and forest management in the context of carbon. This can leave a solid impression with landowners and decision makers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How much carbon is stored in one trillion trees?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/how-much-carbon-is-stored-in-a-trillion-trees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/how-much-carbon-is-stored-in-a-trillion-trees/</guid>
      <description>The short answer: About 5.7 times as much than is currently stored in forests in the lower 48 US states and Alaska. One trillion trees equates to about 101 billion metric tons of carbon stored.&#xD;The Trillion Trees Campaign has been widespread in the news recently. The United States has committed to the initiative, announced at the World Economic Forum in January 2020 and mentioned during President Trump’s annual State of the Union address on 4 February 2020.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four ways to supercharge your scatterplots</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/four-ways-to-supercharge-your-scatterplots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/four-ways-to-supercharge-your-scatterplots/</guid>
      <description>Scatterplots are a go-to visualization with forestry data. Scatterplots show the relationship between two quantitative variables measured on the same object. For example, a tree’s diameter and height.&#xA;There are a few rules for all scatterplots:&#xA;The explanatory variable goes on the x-axis. (This is usually the “easier” measurement to collect.)&#xD;The response variable goes on the y-axis. (This is usually the “harder” measurement to collect.)&#xD;Each observation is a point on the graph.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The three kinds of data scientists in forestry</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/the-three-kinds-of-data-scientists-in-forestry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/the-three-kinds-of-data-scientists-in-forestry/</guid>
      <description>Data scientists are highly sought after professionals across tens of thousands of companies. And there&amp;rsquo;s a difference between what a data scientist does and what a statistician does.&#xA;The field of statistics has been around for centuries, while data science programs at universities are just now beginning to graduate their first students.&#xA;In statistics, hypotheses are evaluated. In data science, hypotheses are generated. Statistics is often considered a primary data analysis technique, while data science is often considered secondary.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
