<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Analytics on </title>
    <link>/tags/analytics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Analytics on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>States with the biggest gains in forest carbon over the last 30 years</title>
      <link>/post/states-with-the-biggest-gains-in-forest-carbon-over-the-last-30-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/states-with-the-biggest-gains-in-forest-carbon-over-the-last-30-years/</guid>
      <description>Trees and forests sequester carbon dioxide and other greenhouse gases from the atmosphere. This makes them a natural climate solution. This also encourages managers to quantify carbon attributes along with the myriad of other benefits that forests provide.
The value of carbon in forests has seen a tremendous increase in recent years. The increase in voluntary forest carbon markets have required analysts to have a better understanding of carbon attributes in the forests they work in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>31 R packages for forest analysts</title>
      <link>/post/31-r-packages-for-forest-analysts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/31-r-packages-for-forest-analysts/</guid>
      <description>The R program is one of the most popular programs being used by forest analysts today. The power of R comes from its diversity of packages. A package is a collection of functions and data sets developed by R users.
The value of using R packages is that someone else might have already written a suite of functions for you. These can include your coworkers, colleagues, and other professionals. R packages are written to be collaborative so that they can be shared with others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forget spreading and gathering your R data, try pivoting instead</title>
      <link>/post/forget-spreading-and-gathering-your-r-data-try-pivoting-instead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/forget-spreading-and-gathering-your-r-data-try-pivoting-instead/</guid>
      <description>Reshaping data from a wide to a long format, or vice versa, is one of the most common data manipulation tasks that analysts need to do. One of my first posts on this blog was on how to do this in R.
That post highlighted the spread() and gather() functions available from the tidyr package. As it turns out, the gather() and spread() functions are still available to use but are no longer under active development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on the American Forestry Conference</title>
      <link>/post/reflections-on-the-american-forestry-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/reflections-on-the-american-forestry-conference/</guid>
      <description>Shawn Baker presents on trends in logging businesses.
Last week I tuned into the American Forestry Conference, a virtual conference on the forest products industry and how forestry businesses can reshape the future US economy. The conference, organized by the Georgia Forestry Association, had 35 speakers that discussed topics such as the challenges and opportunities of the role of forestry in the current and future economic climate. In an email, the organizing committee reported 540 attendees from 26 US states.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forest carbon stocks in every US state</title>
      <link>/post/carbon-by-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/carbon-by-state/</guid>
      <description>photo by Sean MacEntee
In April 2020, the USDA Forest Service published Greenhouse gas emissions and removals from forest land, woodlands, and urban trees in the United States, 1990-2018. What makes this annual report unique is that forest carbon estimates are reported for each US state. Data are available in an appendix which lists forest carbon stocks and flux for each state from 1990 to 2018.
Across the US, forests, urban trees, and harvested wood products are the largest carbon sink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using clustering with logging industry data</title>
      <link>/post/using-clustering-with-logging-industry-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/using-clustering-with-logging-industry-data/</guid>
      <description>A forest products company may not always require a precise numeric answer to solve a problem. Oftentimes, understanding a pattern and how data are clustered can suffice.
The benefit of using pattern recognition techniques is that data need not be labeled prior to analyzing them. In contrast to statistical techniques like regression and classification, identifying patterns can unearth new trends in how data are arranged in your organization.
Clustering is an unsupervised ML algorithm that groups items.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polar area diagrams in celebration of Florence Nightingale</title>
      <link>/post/polar-area-diagrams-in-celebration-of-florence-nightingale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/polar-area-diagrams-in-celebration-of-florence-nightingale/</guid>
      <description>In 1858 the general public was familiar with seeing statistics presented in tables. Visualizations showing statistics and data were not widely used and were difficult to construct. One visualization that was shown to Queen Victoria in this year would live on and continue to be used in the 21st century.
The visualization showed the number of deaths from soldiers in the Crimean War, fought in the 1850s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do loggers feel? Sentiment analysis on the opinions of logging contractors</title>
      <link>/post/how-do-loggers-feel-sentiment-analysis-on-the-opinions-of-logging-contractors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-do-loggers-feel-sentiment-analysis-on-the-opinions-of-logging-contractors/</guid>
      <description>After we conduct a survey, we have a routine for analyzing the data. Summarize the numerical responses and report values like means for specific questions. Group the data into different demographics and report the means within these categories.
If we ask for any qualitative data through comments (e.g., “What is your opinion of X?”), the responses are always worth reading. We often get a lot of insight from reading an individual’s comments, and these comments can unveil new dimensions of our analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting your data into R from Google Sheets</title>
      <link>/post/getting-your-data-into-r-from-google-sheets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-your-data-into-r-from-google-sheets/</guid>
      <description>If you’re like me, more of the data you use on a daily basis are stored in Google Sheets. You might be using fewer Excel spreadsheets and .csv files. I recently researched the most up-to-date ways to import data from an Access database into R. (It had been a while since I imported data from a database.)
Using Google Sheets to store data has several advantages:
Multiple people can collaborate on the same data set,Information entered into a Google Form can populate data in a Google Spreadsheet,Data can be accessed and edited both online and offline, andGoogle Sheets can be converted to Excel spreadsheets, and vice versa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to calculate carbon from board feet and cords</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-calculate-carbon-from-board-feet-and-cords/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-to-calculate-carbon-from-board-feet-and-cords/</guid>
      <description>Foresters and wood buyers are increasingly being asked about the amount of carbon that trees and forests store. However, foresters and wood buyers do not inventory or buy their wood on a carbon basis. Instead, forests in many regions of the US are inventoried and sold using volume measurements such as board feet and cords. If a forest resources professional knows how measurements like wood volume relate to carbon, he or she can feel empowered when discussing the importance of forests and forest management in the context of carbon with landowners and decision makers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disentagling the interactions between site index and disturbance</title>
      <link>/post/disentagling-the-interactions-between-site-index-and-disturbance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/disentagling-the-interactions-between-site-index-and-disturbance/</guid>
      <description>The Black Hills National Forest has been in the news recently after completing a timber sustainability report. In recent years, the Black Hills was one of the US Forest Service’s greatest timber-producing National Forests in the country.
Much of the increase in timber harvest in recent years at the Black Hills National Forest was in response to a deadly mountain pine beetle epidemic. As a result, the new report suggests that current timber harvests are not sustainable into the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forest carbon cheat sheet</title>
      <link>/post/forest-carbon-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/forest-carbon-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>The Forest Carbon Cheat Sheet is a quick reference guide for converting forest carbon measurements and understanding typical carbon values at the tree, stand, and landscape levels.
The Cheast Sheet is updated with the most recent values published in the US Environmental Protection Agency Inventory of U.S. Greenhouse Gas Emissions and Sinks: 1990-2018.
DOWNLOAD (PDF)
DOWNLOAD (JPEG)
The Forest Carbon Cheat Sheet.
If you have questions or comments on the Cheat Sheet, email Matt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Units in forest carbon numbers: a primer</title>
      <link>/post/units-in-forest-carbon-numbers-a-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/units-in-forest-carbon-numbers-a-primer/</guid>
      <description>Forest analysts are increasingly being asked about the amount of carbon that trees and forests store. However, most analysts are trained in summarizing forestry data sets to obtain measurements such as volume and basal area.
If a forest analyst knows how to “speak carbon”, this can leave them feeling empowered when discussing the importance of forests and forest management in the context of carbon. This can leave a solid impression with landowners and decision makers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much carbon is stored in one trillion trees?</title>
      <link>/post/how-much-carbon-is-stored-in-a-trillion-trees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-much-carbon-is-stored-in-a-trillion-trees/</guid>
      <description>The short answer: About 5.7 times as much than is currently stored in forests in the lower 48 US states and Alaska. One trillion trees equates to about 101 billion metric tons of carbon stored.The Trillion Trees Campaign has been widespread in the news recently. The United States has committed to the initiative, announced at the World Economic Forum in January 2020 and mentioned during President Trump’s annual State of the Union address on 4 February 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four ways to supercharge your scatterplots</title>
      <link>/post/four-ways-to-supercharge-your-scatterplots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/four-ways-to-supercharge-your-scatterplots/</guid>
      <description>Scatterplots are a go-to visualization with forestry data. Scatterplots show the relationship between two quantitative variables measured on the same object. For example, a tree’s diameter and height.
There are a few rules for all scatterplots:
The explanatory variable goes on the x-axis. (This is usually the “easier” measurement to collect.)The response variable goes on the y-axis. (This is usually the “harder” measurement to collect.)Each observation is a point on the graph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The three kinds of data scientists in forestry</title>
      <link>/post/the-three-kinds-of-data-scientists-in-forestry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-three-kinds-of-data-scientists-in-forestry/</guid>
      <description>Data scientists are highly sought after professionals across tens of thousands of companies. And there&amp;rsquo;s a difference between what a data scientist does and what a statistician does.
The field of statistics has been around for centuries, while data science programs at universities are just now beginning to graduate their first students.
In statistics, hypotheses are evaluated. In data science, hypotheses are generated. Statistics is often considered a primary data analysis technique, while data science is often considered secondary.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>