<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Forest Measurements on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/tags/forest-measurements/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Forest Measurements on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/tags/forest-measurements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Preliminary thoughts on using the new National Scale Volume and Biomass Estimators</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2024-02-26-preliminary-thoughts-on-using-the-new-national-scale-volume-and-biomass-estimators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2024-02-26-preliminary-thoughts-on-using-the-new-national-scale-volume-and-biomass-estimators/</guid>
      <description>Last fall the USDA Forest Service released the National Scale Volume Biomass (NSVB), a new modeling system for estimating volume, biomass, and carbon stored in individual trees. These new equations replace the previously-used Component Ratio Method (CRM) and are the result of several years of research. Volume, biomass, and carbon attributes in the US Forest Inventory and Analysis (FIA) database have been updated with values from the new equations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How much does adding previous diameter and height growth change FVS predictions?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-10-31-calibrating-fvs-how-much-does-adding-previous-diameter-and-height-growth-change-predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-10-31-calibrating-fvs-how-much-does-adding-previous-diameter-and-height-growth-change-predictions/</guid>
      <description>A brook in western Maine, USA.&#xD;There’s a recent paper by Claudia Herbert and others that’s come up in several meetings I’ve been in the last several months. The paper describes an analysis they used with forecasting forest carbon in California using the Forest Vegetation Simulator. They concluded that using FVS “out-of-the-box”, i.e., with no local calibrations of modifications, “overpredicts carbon sequestration in live trees that remain alive ten years later by 27%, on average.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementing climate adaptive silviculture scenarios in the Forest Vegetation Simulator</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-08-22-implementing-adaptive-silviculture-scenarios-in-the-forest-vegetation-simulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-08-22-implementing-adaptive-silviculture-scenarios-in-the-forest-vegetation-simulator/</guid>
      <description>The Adaptive Silvicultre for Climate Change Project at the Chippewa National Forest, Minnesota, USA. Photo: Josh Kragthorpe.&#xD;If you follow the latest research in forestry, it’s hard not to come across studies relating to adaptive silviculture. In a nutshell, adaptive silviculture is “designed to specifically address climate change impacts and vulnerabilities to meet management goals and objectives.”&#xA;If you’ve ever been on a field tour of a forest that has recently seen a timber harvest and has undergone an adaptive silviculture treatment, you were likely impressed with the complex spatial distribution of residual trees following the harvest.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linear quantile mixed models: applications in forestry</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-07-31-linear-quantile-mixed-models-applications-in-forestry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-07-31-linear-quantile-mixed-models-applications-in-forestry/</guid>
      <description>Example output comparing predictions from three models fit with linear quantile mixed models and one fit using ordinary least squares.&#xD;Mixed models have been used for decades by forest biometricians and statisticians. They have become popular because forestry and natural resources data are often nested, allowing the analyst to account for spatial and temporal correlation among measurements. Forest plots are often measured within stands, stands are located within ownerships, and a collection of ownerships comprise a landscape.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lorey&#39;s height: the remote sensing way to estimate tree height</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-04-21-lorey-s-height-the-remote-sensing-way-to-estimate-tree-height/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-04-21-lorey-s-height-the-remote-sensing-way-to-estimate-tree-height/</guid>
      <description>A canopy of lowland conifer trees in northern Minnesota.&#xD;One of the first things you learn in an forestry field course is how to measure the height of trees. Doing so is tricky, as it’s difficult to locate the tops of many trees in dense forests (especially deciduous ones during leaf-on periods). Many foresters will sub-sample tree heights, for example only measuring the heights for every fifth tree or the four closest trees to plot center.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bootstrapped resampling to model tree biomass</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-04-12-bootstrapped-resampling-estimates-to-predict-tree-height/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-04-12-bootstrapped-resampling-estimates-to-predict-tree-height/</guid>
      <description>In one of the first presentations I gave as a graduate student, I discussed a set of regression equations that fit a nonlinear model predicting a forest growth index for several species. As all graduate students do, I spent considerable time preparing my slides and practicing my talk. The presentation went well.&#xA;I used a data splitting approach in my analysis that I presented on, a common technique that trains a model on a large portion of the data (usually around 70%) then tests it on a smaller portion of data not used in model fitting (usually around 30%).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Imputing missing tree heights from a forest inventory</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-02-15-imputing-missing-tree-heights-from-a-forest-inventory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-02-15-imputing-missing-tree-heights-from-a-forest-inventory/</guid>
      <description>Eastern white pine trees at sunrise in Maine.&#xD;Total height is one of the most useful measurements of a tree, but it’s often not measured. This is because measuring heights takes considerable time and effort. While it may be easy for a forester to measure the diameter of a tree, to obtain a proper measurement of a tree you generally need to walk away from it. This can take a lot of time if there are dozens of trees on a forest inventory plot.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forest carbon cheat sheet: updated for 2022</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-12-21-forest-carbon-cheat-sheet-updated-for-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-12-21-forest-carbon-cheat-sheet-updated-for-2022/</guid>
      <description>The Forest Carbon Cheat Sheet is a quick reference guide for converting forest carbon measurements and understanding typical carbon values at the tree, stand, and landscape levels.&#xA;The Cheat Sheet has been updated with the most recent values published in the US Environmental Protection Agency Inventory of U.S. Greenhouse Gas Emissions and Sinks: 1990-2020.&#xA;DOWNLOAD (PDF)&#xA;DOWNLOAD (PNG)&#xA;The Forest Carbon Cheat Sheet.&#xA;–&#xA;By Matt Russell. Email Matt with any questions or comments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New updates for tools that query Forest Inventory and Analysis data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-11-23-new-updates-for-tools-that-query-forest-inventory-and-analysis-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-11-23-new-updates-for-tools-that-query-forest-inventory-and-analysis-data/</guid>
      <description>The US national forest inventory has information contained from over 130,000 forest inventory plots across the country. Data collected and maintained by the Forest Inventory and Analysis (FIA) program are needed for answering core forestry questions, and having the right tools to help extract specific data that fits the analysis is essential.&#xA;After attending the FIA Science Stakeholder Meeting last week, I was happy to learn about some important updates to two tools that are widely used by forest analysts: the FIA EVALIDator program and the FIA DataMart.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simple volume to weight conversion for US tree species</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-07-27-simple-volume-to-weight-conversion-for-us-tree-species/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-07-27-simple-volume-to-weight-conversion-for-us-tree-species/</guid>
      <description>Foresters are accustomed to converting units of measure from one to another. Data are often collected in one unit of measure (e.g., the height of a tree in feet), but need to be converted to another for some part of the analysis or report (e.g., its height in meters).&#xA;When it comes to calculating the volume of a tree, the number of equations and models are overwhelming. Not only are there a myriad of log rules to determine wood volume of standing timber, but even more volume equations can make determining wood volume for a species of interest a mess.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How &#34;big&#34; are the Big Tree Champions?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-05-23-how-big-are-the-big-tree-champions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-05-23-how-big-are-the-big-tree-champions/</guid>
      <description>You might have heard this before: “I just saw the largest X tree in the state!”&#xA;I have always been curious about the trees that make the list of state tree champions, or “big trees”. For nearly every state in the US, a list of the largest trees of each species are maintained. As landowners and foresters roam the woods, they can report a potential champion tree. (For context, in 2018 a team of wildlife researchers came across the largest jack pine in the US when they were studying wolves in northern Minnesota.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If 50% of a tree&#39;s biomass is carbon, what&#39;s the other half?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-08-22-if-50-of-a-tree-s-biomass-is-carbon-what-s-the-other-half/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-08-22-if-50-of-a-tree-s-biomass-is-carbon-what-s-the-other-half/</guid>
      <description>“You wrote earlier that “since half of biomass is carbon, I multiply by 0.5.” What is the other half of biomass?&#34;&#xA;I was sent this question this question over email last week. As foresters, we’re often concerned with only carbon stored and sequestered in trees. But the are other elements that form the chemical composition of wood. While there are slight deviations to the “50% of biomass in wood is carbon” assumption, it is a statement that provides an approximation about the amount of carbon in wood.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New eBook: Forest Carbon by the Numbers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-08-12-new-ebook-forest-carbon-by-the-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-08-12-new-ebook-forest-carbon-by-the-numbers/</guid>
      <description>Now available on Amazon is Forest Carbon by the Numbers: Understanding the Hottest Forest Product of the 2020s.&#xA;Carbon is becoming a highly valued commodity of forests. Trees sequester carbon dioxide and turn it into wood, storing carbon in forests and long-lived forest products for long time periods. Despite the increased recognition of carbon as a natural climate solution and several emerging markets that monetize it, few professionals in forestry and natural resources have a grasp on the amount and extent of forest carbon in the ecosystems they work in.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testing the assumption: Half of the biomass of a tree is carbon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-06-18-testing-the-assumption-half-of-the-biomass-of-a-tree-is-carbon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-06-18-testing-the-assumption-half-of-the-biomass-of-a-tree-is-carbon/</guid>
      <description>“Half of the biomass of a tree is carbon.” This has been a widely spoken statement made by many foresters and scientists alike. Most forest carbon assessments use the 50% rule and it generally works well.&#xA;In forest analytics, determining the amount of carbon in a tree is first based on estimating its biomass. At the individual tree level, a biomass equation can be developed based on a tree’s diameter, height, species, region, and other tree and stand characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forest carbon cheat sheet: updated for 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-06-12-forest-carbon-cheat-sheet-updated-for-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-06-12-forest-carbon-cheat-sheet-updated-for-2021/</guid>
      <description>The Forest Carbon Cheat Sheet is a quick reference guide for converting forest carbon measurements and understanding typical carbon values at the tree, stand, and landscape levels.&#xA;The Cheat Sheet has been updated with the most recent values published in the US Environmental Protection Agency Inventory of U.S. Greenhouse Gas Emissions and Sinks: 1990-2019.&#xA;DOWNLOAD (PDF)&#xA;DOWNLOAD (JPEG)&#xA;–&#xA;By Matt Russell. Email Matt with any questions or comments. Sign up for my monthly newsletter for in-depth analysis on data and analytics in the forest products industry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coverting forest inventory data from volume to carbon </title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/coverting-wood-scaled-as-weight-to-carbon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/coverting-wood-scaled-as-weight-to-carbon/</guid>
      <description>The amount of carbon in a forest is a key metric that decision-makers want to know. Accurate estimates of forest carbon are needed if a landowner is interested in enrolling a forest into carbon markets.&#xA;Unfortunately, most forest inventories continue to measure the amount of wood in a stand in terms of the volume it contains. Forest analysts also rely on historical forest inventory data to project future forest structure and composition - it is not unlikely to rely on inventory data that are more than 20 years old.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trends in forest carbon papers in the last 20 years</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/trends-in-forest-carbon-literature/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/trends-in-forest-carbon-literature/</guid>
      <description>The number of peer-reviewed research publications on forest carbon has exploded in recent decades. From the signings of the Kyoto Protocol in 1997 to the Paris Agreement in 2015, much of the science and research conducted has been in response to the global challenges and opportunities that forests provide by sequestering and storing carbon.&#xA;Forest carbon has also been increasingly studied in forest management and silvicultural practices. New technologies and remote sensing have also brought about new ways to inventory forests for the biomass and carbon they store.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ask how you want your data - and be specific</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/ask-how-how-want-your-data-and-be-specific/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/ask-how-how-want-your-data-and-be-specific/</guid>
      <description>I have been analyzing the submissions to the University of Minnesota Extension’s Tree and Woodland Carbon Capture Challenge. The Challenge is an activity that asked Minnesotans to measure trees and woodlands to observe how much carbon they sequester over a year.&#xA;The audience that participated in this activity included homeowners and private woodland owners with a love for trees. In total, 26 people measured an individual tree and typed their measurements into a Google Form answering the question “What is the diameter of your tree, measured in inches?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31 R packages for forest analysts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/31-r-packages-for-forest-analysts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/31-r-packages-for-forest-analysts/</guid>
      <description>The R program is one of the most popular programs being used by forest analysts today. The power of R comes from its diversity of packages. A package is a collection of functions and data sets developed by R users.&#xA;The value of using R packages is that someone else might have already written a suite of functions for you. These can include your coworkers, colleagues, and other professionals. R packages are written to be collaborative so that they can be shared with others.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to calculate carbon from board feet and cords</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/how-to-calculate-carbon-from-board-feet-and-cords/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/how-to-calculate-carbon-from-board-feet-and-cords/</guid>
      <description>Foresters and wood buyers are increasingly being asked about the amount of carbon that trees and forests store. However, foresters and wood buyers do not inventory or buy their wood on a carbon basis. Instead, forests in many regions of the US are inventoried and sold using volume measurements such as board feet and cords. If a forest resources professional knows how measurements like wood volume relate to carbon, he or she can feel empowered when discussing the importance of forests and forest management in the context of carbon with landowners and decision makers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forest carbon cheat sheet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/forest-carbon-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/forest-carbon-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>The Forest Carbon Cheat Sheet is a quick reference guide for converting forest carbon measurements and understanding typical carbon values at the tree, stand, and landscape levels.&#xA;The Cheast Sheet is updated with the most recent values published in the US Environmental Protection Agency Inventory of U.S. Greenhouse Gas Emissions and Sinks: 1990-2018.&#xA;DOWNLOAD (PDF)&#xA;DOWNLOAD (JPEG)&#xA;The Forest Carbon Cheat Sheet.&#xA;If you have questions or comments on the Cheat Sheet, email Matt.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Units in forest carbon numbers: a primer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/units-in-forest-carbon-numbers-a-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/units-in-forest-carbon-numbers-a-primer/</guid>
      <description>Forest analysts are increasingly being asked about the amount of carbon that trees and forests store. However, most analysts are trained in summarizing forestry data sets to obtain measurements such as volume and basal area.&#xA;If a forest analyst knows how to “speak carbon”, this can leave them feeling empowered when discussing the importance of forests and forest management in the context of carbon. This can leave a solid impression with landowners and decision makers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How much carbon is stored in one trillion trees?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/how-much-carbon-is-stored-in-a-trillion-trees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/how-much-carbon-is-stored-in-a-trillion-trees/</guid>
      <description>The short answer: About 5.7 times as much than is currently stored in forests in the lower 48 US states and Alaska. One trillion trees equates to about 101 billion metric tons of carbon stored.&#xD;The Trillion Trees Campaign has been widespread in the news recently. The United States has committed to the initiative, announced at the World Economic Forum in January 2020 and mentioned during President Trump’s annual State of the Union address on 4 February 2020.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which forest biometrics researchers get the most citations?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/which-forest-biometrics-faculty-get-the-most-citations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/which-forest-biometrics-faculty-get-the-most-citations/</guid>
      <description>Researchers in the forest and natural resource sciences are measured by their productivity: how many publications they write and how many times those publications are cited by other researchers. Researchers that have many publications that are cited in the literature by others generally have rewarding careers and are promoted.&#xA;In 2017 I wrote a blog post for the Ecological Society of America’s Early Career Ecologist section that provided some evidence that early-career scientists publish earlier in their careers compared to more senior researchers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to calculate how much carbon is in a tree</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/how-to-calculate-how-much-carbon-is-in-a-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/how-to-calculate-how-much-carbon-is-in-a-tree/</guid>
      <description>Carbon is perhaps the most important attribute in trees today. Forests in the United States sequester about 11% of the total CO2 emissions every year, making them an important tool to combat future global changes. Having accurate models that represent how much carbon is stored in trees is essential for understanding their carbon sequestration potential and are widely used in forest carbon accounting tools.&#xA;Most equations that predict the amount carbon in a tree start with first predicting its biomass.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A 50-year history of forest measurements by analyzing Forest Measurements</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/a-50-year-history-of-forest-measurements-by-analyzing-forest-measurements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/a-50-year-history-of-forest-measurements-by-analyzing-forest-measurements/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve even taken a course in forest measurements, you likely used Forest Measurements as the textbook. The first edition of forest measurements was published in 1967 by Thomas Eugene Avery and included a number of topics related to forest inventory, sampling forest resources, and tree and stand measurements.&#xA;The book recently published its 6th edition in 2018 and is available through Waveland Press. Investigating how the book has incorporated new topics gives insights into the advances of the field of forest measurements:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
