<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Timber Harvesting on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/tags/timber-harvesting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Timber Harvesting on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/tags/timber-harvesting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Placing harvested wood products in the forest carbon discussion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/events/2024-03-28-placing-harvested-wood-products-in-the-forest-carbon-discussion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/events/2024-03-28-placing-harvested-wood-products-in-the-forest-carbon-discussion/</guid>
      <description>This presentation provides a background on harvested wood products from a carbon perspective, highlighting the role that wood durability and longevity plays in understanding how different wood product types contribute to carbon storage. It also describes a recent analysis that summarized annual harvest removals from Northeastern US states to estimate the longevity of harvested wood stored in products in use and tracked their decay to landfills and the atmosphere. A few tools are highlighted which show how foresters can determine wood product storage using forest inventory and timber sale data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pandemic assistance to the forest industry: a summary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/events/2022-09-27-pandemic-assistance-to-the-forest-industry-a-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/events/2022-09-27-pandemic-assistance-to-the-forest-industry-a-summary/</guid>
      <description>Forest products and timber harvesting and hauling businesses secured nearly $5 billion of federal funds through the Paycheck Protection Program and Pandemic Assistance to Timber Harvesters and Haulers programs to combat economic challenges presented by the COVID-19 pandemic. These slides were presented at the 2022 Society of American Foresters Convention in Baltimore, MD.&#xA;READ THE SLIDES.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
