<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teaching Statistics on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/tags/teaching-statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Teaching Statistics on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/tags/teaching-statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s okay to look at the solutions for statistics and data science exercises</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-07-15-it-s-okay-to-look-at-solutions-for-statistics-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2023-07-15-it-s-okay-to-look-at-solutions-for-statistics-problems/</guid>
      <description>The cover of a document titled “Statistics in Natural Resources: Applications with R: Exercise Soultions.”&#xD;A few years ago I completed the RStudio Instructor training course. It was a multi-day, online training workshop and I learned less about the ins and outs of coding and analysis in R, but more about the strategies and philosophy of teaching data science principles.&#xA;The course prepares instructors to teach the principles of the tidyverse, especially drawing on the concepts for the excellent book R for Data Science.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doing statistics in the tidyverse: exploring the infer package</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-12-14-doing-statistics-in-the-tidyverse-exploring-the-infer-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-12-14-doing-statistics-in-the-tidyverse-exploring-the-infer-package/</guid>
      <description>If you use R software for your data analysis, you are likely familiar with the tidyverse. The tidyverse package is a “megapackage” in R that includes several packages that import, reshape, and visualize data in a consistent manner, among other tasks.&#xA;Like many analysts, I use the tidyverse suite of functions often for importing, wrangling, and visualizing data. More and more I’m using the tidymodels package to apply statistical modeling techniques like regression and random forests on data I work with.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to spot poor data analyses</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-10-20-how-to-spot-poor-data-analyses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-10-20-how-to-spot-poor-data-analyses/</guid>
      <description>Being an excellent data analyst requires you to understand the techniques that go into analyzing data and how to communicate them effectively. While having a foundation in statistics and the quantitative sciences is essential, the most effective data analysts communicate information that influences decision makers.&#xA;Unfortunately, there are plenty of examples of sloppy data analyses that distort the reality of what data can tell us. As an example, genetics researchers have found that Microsoft Excel’s autocorrecting feature had led to errors in 30% of gene list observations over a six year span.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>P-ing in the woods: p-values in forest science</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-10-10-p-ing-in-the-woods-p-values-in-forest-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-10-10-p-ing-in-the-woods-p-values-in-forest-science/</guid>
      <description>A meme about p-values. Hat tip to Matt Dancho for the idea for the graphic.&#xD;The statistics community has had a lot of discussion in recent years about the role of p-values and statistical significance. This has led some to question if we’re relying too much on them as a way of interpreting results from a statistical analysis.&#xA;The “p” in p-value stands for probability, or the probability under a statistical model that a summary of the data would be equal to or more extreme than its observed value.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New book: Statistics in Natural Resources: Applications with R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-07-20-new-book-statistics-in-natural-resources-applications-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2022-07-20-new-book-statistics-in-natural-resources-applications-with-r/</guid>
      <description>At the start of the pandemic in 2020, I was worried. Not just for the serious global health impacts, but also for the workload I would soon be faced with.&#xA;I taught an introductory statistics course for graduate students in the natural resources and agricultural disciplines, and was scrambling to find out how I would migrate my course material to an online, asynchronous format.&#xA;At the same time, I was searching for a different textbook to use for the course.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What statistics students in natural resources want to learn more about</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-12-22-what-statistics-students-want-to-learn-more-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-12-22-what-statistics-students-want-to-learn-more-about/</guid>
      <description>As the holidays approach, it’s always a great time of year to reflect back and look forward. This post will describe my approach to this as it relates to a class that just wrapped up for the Fall 2021 semester.&#xA;I instruct the course NR 5021: Statistics for Agricultural and Natural Resources Professionals at the University of Minnesota. The class has between 25 and 40 graduate students enrolled in a given year, a mix between students studying natural resources, agriculture, and plant sciences.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How well does the &#34;quick and dirty&#34; standard deviation approximation work?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-06-04-how-well-does-the-quick-and-dirty-standard-deviation-approximation-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2021-06-04-how-well-does-the-quick-and-dirty-standard-deviation-approximation-work/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Chris Liverani on Unsplash.&#xA;The standard deviation measures the dispersion of individual samples around a mean value. It is one of the most useful measures in forestry and natural resources because it quantifies the “noise” in a sample of data.&#xA;When I was learning statistics in an introductory course, I was shown a formula to approximate the standard deviation. Rather than needing to calculate how far each observation was from the mean value, a key component of the standard deviation calculation, this formula only required knowing the largest and smallest value in the data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Google Forms to analyze confidence intervals: a teaching statistics activity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/using-google-forms-to-analyze-confidence-intervals-a-teaching-statistics-activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/using-google-forms-to-analyze-confidence-intervals-a-teaching-statistics-activity/</guid>
      <description>This post describes how the concepts of confidence intervals can be taught to students. The ideal participants are undergraduate students in an introductory statistics. The in-class activity reveals to students that most people are overconfident in their estimation of uncertainty. The activity uses the example of moose, a charismatic wildlife species in Minnesota.&#xA;Introduction&#xD;Demonstrations of data and statistical concepts are effective when they are designed with a structure that encourages participation in the classroom 1.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
