<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Communicating Data on </title>
    <link>/tags/communicating-data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Communicating Data on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/communicating-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Four ways to supercharge your scatterplots</title>
      <link>/post/four-ways-to-supercharge-your-scatterplots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/four-ways-to-supercharge-your-scatterplots/</guid>
      <description>Scatterplots are a go-to visualization with forestry data. Scatterplots show the relationship between two quantitative variables measured on the same object. For example, a tree’s diameter and height.
There are a few rules for all scatterplots:
The explanatory variable goes on the x-axis. (This is usually the “easier” measurement to collect.)The response variable goes on the y-axis. (This is usually the “harder” measurement to collect.)Each observation is a point on the graph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should foresters keep saying “statistically significant”?</title>
      <link>/post/should-foresters-keep-saying-statistically-significant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/should-foresters-keep-saying-statistically-significant/</guid>
      <description>The statistics community has had a lot of discussion in recent years about the role of p -values and statistical significance. What does this mean for forest biometricians and analysts that have traditionally used p -values and tests of significance in their daily work?
The American Statistical Association’s August 2019 edition of their magazine Significance has a number of great articles on significance. They even refer to the term as “the S word”:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quickly explore your timber cruise data with six lines of code</title>
      <link>/post/explore-your-timber-cruise-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/explore-your-timber-cruise-data/</guid>
      <description>Data from timber cruises and other forest inventories need to be clean and easy to interpret. Time can be lost in the field and office if data were collected sloppily, were measured in the field without a protocol, or are otherwise “messy” with lots of errors.
A data-checking routine can save time, money, and resources. Identifying potential data inaccuracies or inconsistencies soon after they’re collected can help eliminate any inappropriate decisions that are made from those data further down the line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presenting regression results better with forest plots</title>
      <link>/post/presenting-regression-results-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/presenting-regression-results-better/</guid>
      <description>I was inspired by Sara Richter’s presentation at the 2019 Conference on Statistical Practice titled “Easy Ways to Make Data Visualizations More Effective”. One of the themes I took away from Sara’s presentation was that data visualization needs to be practiced, but good data visualization doesn’t need to be difficult to be done well.
When presenting results from a regression, people often use tables. While this is good if we need the true value of something, tables may not be good if we seek to convey general trends in our results.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>