<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Statistics on </title>
    <link>/tags/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Statistics on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to determine accuracy of classification models (with forestry data)</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-determine-accuracy-of-classification-models-with-forestry-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-to-determine-accuracy-of-classification-models-with-forestry-data/</guid>
      <description>Classification is the process when you predict something, and that something is a class or label. It’s widely used when analyzing and modeling forestry data. Data scientists use if often as one of the many machine learning algorithms.
You might have learned about classification in the context of logistic regression. In logistic regression, your outcome is a binary class of data. For example, a tree can be alive or dead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The three kinds of data scientists in forestry</title>
      <link>/post/the-three-kinds-of-data-scientists-in-forestry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-three-kinds-of-data-scientists-in-forestry/</guid>
      <description>Data scientists are highly sought after professionals across tens of thousands of companies. And there&amp;rsquo;s a difference between what a data scientist does and what a statistician does.
The field of statistics has been around for centuries, while data science programs at universities are just now beginning to graduate their first students.
In statistics, hypotheses are evaluated. In data science, hypotheses are generated. Statistics is often considered a primary data analysis technique, while data science is often considered secondary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruffed grouse and West Nile: A review of the binomial distribution</title>
      <link>/post/ruffed-grouse-and-west-nile-a-review-of-the-binomial-distribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ruffed-grouse-and-west-nile-a-review-of-the-binomial-distribution/</guid>
      <description>There’s been a lot of talk in the wildlife community about the West Nile virus and its impacts on ruffed grouse populations.
In 2018, a multi-state effort examined the presence of West Nile virus in ruffed grouse populations across the US Lake States. The study concluded that while the West Nile virus was present in the region, grouse that are exposed to West Nile do not always die and can survive.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>