<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>climate change on </title>
    <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/tags/climate-change/</link>
    <description>Recent content in climate change on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arbor-analytics.com/tags/climate-change/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CO2 offsets and trips to the family cabin</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-11-27-co2-offsets-and-trips-to-the-family-cabin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/2021-11-27-co2-offsets-and-trips-to-the-family-cabin/</guid>
      <description>Often I think that if the numbers behind forest carbon estimates were easier to calculate and interpret, we’d all have a better understanding of the carbon stored and sequestered in our forests. It starts simple when we say that “half of the biomass of a tree is carbon”. But beyond that, transitions between gases and solids and conversions between metric and English units quickly add complexity.
The true amount of forest carbon is only measured in detailed research studies, yet we discuss carbon stocks like they’re known values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate 21: what it says about forest carbon</title>
      <link>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/climate-21-what-it-says-about-forest-carbon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arbor-analytics.com/post/climate-21-what-it-says-about-forest-carbon/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a transition coming to the White House, and forests and climate change will be a large part of it.
In late 2020, the Climate 21 Project drafted a series of transition memos highlighting recommendations and opportunities related to climate change and the federal government&amp;rsquo;s response. The Climate 21 Project includes the insights of over 150 experts with government expertise related to climate change.
The Department of Agriculture (USDA) memo recognizes the role that the forestry and agriculture sectors play in climate mitigation and adaptation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
